Krish NAik: Okay, so a few things. First, I'll be talking about
Krish NAik: the, main.py, that is our fast API, Fail.
Krish NAik: Okay? Then, in the second one.
Krish NAik: We'll be talking about the Lambda adapter that I have. Okay, the mangom adapter, basically, that one. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: the…
Krish NAik: the Lambda handler, I think. That is the name of the file.
Krish NAik: This is very specific to AWS Lambda.
Krish NAik: Hadap-dal.
Krish NAik: And then, again, we'll be going through the, deployment, because in the deployment, I've done a few changes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this time, what I have done, rather than picking up directly a base image from DockerUp.
Krish NAik: I am creating the base image, so a two-step strategy…
Krish NAik: That I have taken, for the deployment. Okay, so we'll be talking about that deployment. So, rest, everything is fine, only, if you remember in the last class.
Krish NAik: The deployment build was taking a lot of time.
Krish NAik: So there, I have taken a two approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… to approach… One is building.
Krish NAik: the VF image.
Krish NAik: Okay, and why I build a build? Okay, because, when I checked, majorly in the deployment, if you know that, we were using this command, DNF.
Krish NAik: Okay, and as we are working with Lambda-based images, AWS Lambda, okay, so there, whenever I'm doing an installation, this DNF installation is taking a lot of time. Okay, so that's why, like, building the OS-level dependencies was taking a lot of time.
Krish NAik: So, what I have done, I've, made it into, like.
Krish NAik: two-step approach. One is the OS-level dependencies.
Krish NAik: This will be only done once.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then comes your… application-level dependencies.
Krish NAik: your main Fast API application that we have built, So, in that way.
Krish NAik: I have kept it. Okay, and for, both of them, I've kept, separate ECR reports.
Krish NAik: Okay, for this one, a separate ECR repo, and for this one, also a separate ECR repo.
Krish NAik: And another level of optimization, that,
Krish NAik: I have done. It is with respect to the… Build up docklinks, because…
Krish NAik: Previously, I have taken the default dockling, which was based on the original GPU build, but right now, I have added the flag for only CPU build, because in our Lambda environment, we only be having any type of GPU, so it is not required. So, very specifically there, I'll be taking only the
Krish NAik: Docling.
Krish NAik: CPU build. I've kept it in a separate, because it just…
Krish NAik: 3 to 4 keywords that you need to add for this particular package.
Krish NAik: Okay, because automatically, previously it was close to 270 packages.
Krish NAik: But after that, it will reduce to close to 200.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are few of the things that, we'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: And then, we will do the deployment again. Okay, so you can take up my fork, and again, we can do that. But before, taking up the fork, a few things I'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let's talk about, tomorrow's discussion. Tomorrow's discussion, so I think Project 3 will be starting next week, okay?
Krish NAik: So… Okay.
Krish NAik: The first one will be, if you remember in the Advanced Act tutorial, I have kept something with respect to query transformations. How many of you remember?
Krish NAik: I have not discussed that particular notebook, but I'm planning that let's complete it. It's a small notebook, only the query transformations.
Krish NAik: Okay? Then we will come to Sirag and Nesarag.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we'll see that.
Krish NAik: and Esrad.
Krish NAik: Okay, so tomorrow, a little bit of theory and simple notebook implementations, because the third one, I think… have I uploaded that in GitHub? Because… GitHub…
Krish NAik: Repose… Put the semantic, highlight, corrective cell record, yes.
Krish NAik: So, like, this is where I think the hybrid part and other things that I have taken into account. So, this is a hybrid RAG with CRAG and a SRAG implementation. Okay, so before this particular implementation.
Krish NAik: I think we'll be talking about the theoretical part. So next week, I think we'll be talking about this report, which will be your third project, but I have added much more advanced patterns there, because I think in your syllabus, it was very much late in the module.
Krish NAik: CRAG, SRAG, AdaptiveRag, okay, but I have taken the implementation there, because CRAG helps you to improve your retrieval quality, and similarly, self-reflective RAG helps you to improve your
Krish NAik: LLM generation, content quality, okay? So, that's why these two things I have added on top of your hybrid RAM implementation.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I, hope everybody got, so this will be, like, next week's agenda. Okay, but before that, we have to understand, so tomorrow we'll be going through the papers, also the research papers of CRAG and SRAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why that query transformation part, inside the query transformation, a lot of different type of transformation examples, I think last time I have kept it, so pretty much easy, because there are… most of the things are based on prompt.
Krish NAik: Okay, so prompt level changes, that needs to be done. And then CRAC and SRAC, so that by next week, we are ready for Project 3. Because Hybrid Rack, I have already taught, re-ranking, I have taught.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think we are good to go with Project 3, then.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I hope for everybody, whatever the things that I have discussed at scale, like, what I'm going to do today, what I am going to do tomorrow, and what we are going to do next week.
Krish NAik: One hour training? Alright, one hour training part, let me see then, tomorrow, or somewhere around. Like, if I need an extra class, I can take that for…
Krish NAik: Okay, because it's done on schema and some golden examples, so yes, we can take that.
Krish NAik: Not an issue.
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, let's complete this part, and then we will start, because again, for the deployment, only one thing that needs to be created from the site
Krish NAik: The OS level dependency, so for that, I've created a separate report, because I need to… this is my base image.
Krish NAik: Okay, so rather than picking Python 3.12 for Lambda, okay, I have built my own image, and I have kept it. Every time.
Krish NAik: the base image will be picked up from my private ECR repo, and on top of that, we'll be building our application.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this repo needs to be created. I have added that particular flag also.
Krish NAik: But, whenever you are creating a repo, you need that URI part, okay? So, this level, if I… I can… I cannot automate it, so manually it needs to be created only once.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think we are good to go with…
Krish NAik: Viffin is asking, why we are creating our own base image. The main purpose is, this base image, if we are not, creating by ourselves, then every time, these two things. One is your OS-level dependencies and application-level dependencies. Every time it's taking.
Krish NAik: Like, that, close to 15 to 20 minutes. The idea is to reduce that, because this takes around, I can say, close to…
Krish NAik: The major build takes, this is around 15 minutes. This is much faster, actually.
Krish NAik: So, if this is fixed going forward, then directly I can take the waste-level dependencies, and this will be much faster. I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: So I'm taking the base image, so that again and again during the CICD pipeline, I don't need to install the OS-level dependencies. I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: We'll be much more focused only on application-level dependencies.
Krish NAik: And if something changes with respect to OS-level dependencies.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, in the last class, a few things with respect to carbon, things that I have added. Then again, we'll be rebuilding that. But I feel that, every time working with OS-level dependencies is not required, majorly, the changes that comes even with respect to deployment, it will be based on application level.
Krish NAik: Do we also have to create our own base image? You don't have to do it automatically in the script, I have taken that in the CICD pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay? Manually, you can create it, I have added that script also. Okay, so if I show you…
Krish NAik: Just wait, okay.
Krish NAik: So, I think this is the build base image.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: So this is the script that we have, okay, to build the base image. And the same script even I have. You can see a lot of eco-statements are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… this is your main one, but this is only for locally, if you want to do the build, because actually there is only one command. This is the command.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, but I have taken that, core, the base one, and for that, I have taken this Dockerfile lambda.base, okay?
Krish NAik: So, that's why.
Krish NAik: So, creating a personal… because this DNF and all these installations, which are the dependencies of docklinks. Otherwise, your PDF and other things, like,
Krish NAik: Like, through Docklinks, if you want to, do out, table detection or any other things, okay, it won't work.
Krish NAik: So, your docklings will fill. So, because of that, I have taken this step, where only
Krish NAik: The voice level dependencies, you can see all the DNF installed. This takes a lot of time, so I've kept things separately, and only the application things separately.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think we are good to go.
Krish NAik: Let me know, guys, can we start?
Krish NAik: Because, first of all, I'll be talking about the Fast API file.
Krish NAik: So, this FastAPI file is actually where you have all the routes. Whenever you look into the Swagger UI, you guys can see the different type of routes that we have. So, all those routes are configured in this particular file.
Krish NAik: Alright, so first of all, okay, so let me just go through the chat, and then I will… Matthews is asking, will you take us through the base image creation? Yes, the base image creation is just, like, it's the same thing, and…
Krish NAik: I just showed you the file also. Again, I'll be showing you during the deployment phase, Matthews. Do we also have to create our own base image? Not required. Locally, it's not required. Because doing DNF installations, it's only during build time which is required.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, not need to do it locally. Because if you do it locally, then again, push it, not necessary. Rather than… it's a one-time thing, probably it might take 20 to 25 minutes.
Krish NAik: For the base image and the application-level dependencies, so… Because once the base image is done, for the next time, the deployments will be much faster, within 4 to 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: AgeMT, yeah, Agentee Langra was the only topic, so, like, Langra will come, because I think, once we have discussed Project 3, then I'll be talking about
Krish NAik: Multimodal rag, graph RAG,
Krish NAik: Okay, before that haystack, one or two classes, just to… because it's another framework, like Lama Index, so that part will be up covered, because my priority will be much more towards multimodal RAG and graph RAG, these two things. I am planning, like, new 4G, but, Neo 4G is not very optimal for that.
Krish NAik: So I'm planning to get Falker DB. Falker is much better.
Krish NAik: And then, with respect to metadata enrichment, also,
Krish NAik: I want to discuss, because this month, very specifically, like, Gleaner got a lot of highlights.
Krish NAik: in the community, so the Gleaner, GLINER. Anybody has explored Gleaner?
Krish NAik: or lang extract.
Krish NAik: these two… For entity recognition tasks based on your documents.
Krish NAik: Anybody else explored lang extract?
Krish NAik: Our cleaner, okay? Heard about it, but never used. No, no, there was no class on Wednesday.
Krish NAik: One day I was sick, even today also, I have fever a little bit, but I thought about…
Krish NAik: We know the deployment fees, we have to just wait and wait, okay? So that's why.
Krish NAik: So, cleaner part, lang extract part.
Krish NAik: A lot of things are there to discuss, like,
Krish NAik: I'll be sharing a few repos and other things, because… let me see, because I think, few extra classes going forward I'll be taking, okay? Because hallucination, detection.
Krish NAik: semantic highlighting, same catchy, okay, a lot of things are there, even which is not there in your syllabus. Okay, but I will try to cover, because
Krish NAik: according to the last past 2 months, I feel that these are pretty much going around in the RAC community.
Krish NAik: What is the use case of Gleaner? Generally, for metadata enrichment, it is used wrong.
Krish NAik: Okay? Project 3 will start noon.
Krish NAik: Right now, only I have told guys, Project 3 again, PAY, you are asking, already I have written that.
Krish NAik: Okay
Krish NAik: I'm nothing. So tomorrow will be much more, Jupyter Notebook-based discussion, the fundamentals, the query, transformations, leader, etc. Next week, Project 3 will start.
Krish NAik: Mmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, sorry, it's your requirement, because right now, it's… I'm much more focused towards that. Will you cover page index? Page Intex is interesting, I can say. A vector-less, architecture, I have done the work, but again, it's a paid product.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why. If you want, I can show you a demo of that, probably, by taking an extra class paramedic, okay? So, it's a good one.
Krish NAik: But, every time working with, like, without that also. Because right now, I feel that in the market, it's much more about…
Krish NAik: I don't know how many of you know, like, working with agentic file-based systems.
Krish NAik: That one that we have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so guys, let's start the session.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, quickly, we will be going through the overview. A lot of things are there, because
Krish NAik: I think next week I'll be traveling home, so I'll be having a lot of time, so extra classes I can plan going forward. As I told you, like, starting from mid of Feb till March every week, then I can cover a lot of topics which are not included in the syllabus. That's why.
Krish NAik: So, desktop… I think this is the third one.
Krish NAik: Good justice.
Krish NAik: Rahul Pariah is asking, The fusion part, already I have discussed.
Krish NAik: Heidi, I have discussed… Brown, please go through.
Krish NAik: If you have missed the classes, these things I've already discussed.
Krish NAik: I think in class, everybody remembers RRF, RSF, All right.
Krish NAik: So, let's get to one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a main.py file, which is inside the app folder. This is the main, I can say, fast API entry point for the web application that we have built.
Krish NAik: So, few common things, okay, so typing, fast API responses, JSON response, data leap, okay? So, few common boilerplates for our Fast API application. And then comes our core, services from the app, okay?
Krish NAik: So, first of all, like, from config import settings, if you remember all those settings which are required. Okay, so inside our config.py, so all those things that I am importing. Then comes our logging configuration.
Krish NAik: Then comes our document service, pass documents, so these are all services I have already discussed. So in this case, I am directly calling them one by one.
Krish NAik: Then, embedding surveys, vector surveys, RAG surveys, text-to-SQL, query routing, catcher service.
Krish NAik: Okay, the catcher service is the document catcher service, the query catcher service is the actual one which we are using for Redis.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then comes a few validators, like, from UTLE in the…
Krish NAik: Utils I have kept, so here, like, validation errors, file validator, so all those validations, I'm importing right now in my main.py.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright.
Krish NAik: Right now, don't write in the chat with respect to deployment, Amar. Focus on the thing that I am discussing.
Krish NAik: Alright, so then, once the core imports are done.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I'll be setting up my main login, so initializing my login.
Krish NAik: Then, like, OPEC is a… OPEC and Redis. Both the implementations are optional. It's not necessary that you will be using it. If you don't feel so, that's why I've kept a simple try and accept block. First, for OPEC. OPEC, you have actually passed
Krish NAik: in the .env, then only it will be required, okay? And otherwise, if you have done the installation. So that's why the try and catch block that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Okay, try an exception.
Krish NAik: No, it's not New Relic.
Krish NAik: DataRog… okay, those Sentry, those are much advanced.
Krish NAik: Okay, moment.
Krish NAik: I can say. Opic, you cannot compare. Opic is to a certain level, but really, New Relic, they do a much more detailed post-mortem of your entire appeal.
Krish NAik: OPEC is not, because for OPEC, very specifically on top of specific routes, for example, I want to track a particular thing
Krish NAik: about a fast API route, then I will just add the decorator on top of that route. So in that way, only those functionality I'll be tracking, okay? So it's not like New Relic, but New Relic is much better.
Krish NAik: Similarly, Sentry, much better in production when you used it.
Krish NAik: That's why they come with a cost.
Krish NAik: OPEC is totally free and open source.
Krish NAik: Alright, so then initializing our FastAPI app. So, as you can see, these are the common things with respect to FastAPI initialization.
Krish NAik: Then, my global services. So, this is very, very important, because, whenever we are starting our application, so initially we start with none. Later on, we have a check based on the API keys are available or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's our embedding service, vector service, rack service, SQL service, catcher service, okay, and the query catcher service. All these things. So initially, none if the environment variables are available, other… if you don't pass the environment variable, directly we'll see false-false.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody remembers that, okay, in the FastAPI application, whenever we have done it.
Krish NAik: Then comes your upload directory and the cache directory. Now, these two things will be different for your local execution and for your lambda execution, so that's why, if you remember in our config.py, we have that if-else parameter, based on the environment selection.
Krish NAik: Because it totally depends upon year.
Krish NAik: back-end storage. If your backend storage is based on local, then it will be different. If it's based on Sethil, it will be different.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I have a simple health route and the return type, simply, I pass this particular dictionary.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, simply, this is the return type of our entire, I can say,
Krish NAik: Health route that I have. Okay, so through this, I track. Okay, and generally, like, all those things, service initialization, so there, this part, I look through the settings. Okay, so, because in my config, everything is defined. So, from there, I pick it up.
Krish NAik: Okay, Raul is asking, do you have a teardown scripts for the AWS infrastructure, as we had deployed last time?
Krish NAik: No, it's a serverless, but, with your app, Terraform, or follow me? Yes, you can do that, because, then that, manual creation, or PCR, whichever the thing that we are doing manually, everything can be automated.
Krish NAik: like, Pulumi or through Terraform. There's a route. That can be done. I don't have that script because I've not done the implementation.
Krish NAik: probably in project 3 or 4, I can take up Pulumi.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Then comes your info route, a very similar type of information. Okay, so this route, again, like, it will be loaded up based on your .env, so your document rack, SQL,
Krish NAik: And as you can see, these are direct dict-based information, which I'm directly returning. What is the Python version?
Krish NAik: Okay, so these things I'm actually looking from this, environment.
Krish NAik: of your actual system. And based on that, we are returning the total number of endpoints. Okay, now, through this, it becomes much easier to track anything. But again, here, I have not kept all the endpoints with respect to clearing the cache, clearing the vectors.
Krish NAik: The core ones… Those only guys kept it.
Krish NAik: Now comes your slash route, okay? Again, like, in the slash route, just I have kept one, if you want to check the swagger UI through slash docs, otherwise you can call the slash health slash info. This is a direct return type of a simple route, because, you know, whenever you are hitting
Krish NAik: our core application, and for initial testing, we always use the slash docs for swaggerUI. So, this is a simple dict return type.
Krish NAik: Alright, now coming to, the actual routes which are much more important, important.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can see app.post. Okay, now this is a post call. The routers upload, so in this particular upload, as, like, PDF, docs, JSON, text, whatever, the file type that we are passing.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, for this particular route, at the red track, name is equal to upload document. Now, this is for OPEC tracking, that I have kept it, at the red track. Okay? So, similarly, for any type of route, if you want to do a tracking, you can add this particular decorator, add the red track, or OPEC.
Krish NAik: Now, async dev upload document, what is the key here? The key is this file. It means that if you want to use Postman or Requestly, again, from there, if you want to pass it through our multi-part platform, then this is the actual key.
Krish NAik: And this key, always remember, because if you don't know the key, you cannot do the upload. So, file is the actual key through which you can upload the files.
Krish NAik: Now, to… once, because once you are uploading the document, so what are the steps that needs to be done? So, all those things will be, checking that whether it's available or not. So, first of all.
Krish NAik: Like, the embedding service is available or not, the vector service is available, the catcher service, and the query catcher service. All those things. And out of this, these two things are optional, and these two things are compulsion.
Krish NAik: Because without your embedding service, and without your vector service, there is no purpose of uploading anything. Okay, so that's why the global variable definition.
Krish NAik: Hmm… I have kept them in global because I do a check whenever we start the application bulge.
Krish NAik: That's why I've kept them as global. Because initially, whenever I start my application, I check all the services are available or not.
Krish NAik: Okay? Then comes my file validator, so this is available in utils. Okay, so right now I'm just validating, the file extension types, okay, through this.
Krish NAik: Now, one by one, all those global things, I will check if they are available or not, okay? So that's why if the embedding service or the vector service is not available, do you think that the route should work? So that's why, simply, document rack services, please configure your OpenAI key and Pinecone API key in .env.
Krish NAik: That I have taken that. Now, once you have uploaded the document and the validation of the extension types have been passed, then in the next step is basically to save the file.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, where to save the file? So, very specifically for that, the upload directory. Now, this is another environment, because this upload directory changes according to your backend storage selection, whether for S3 or local. Then we are opening the file, and we are saving it, okay?
Krish NAik: Then, for S3, we are doing a very specific task with respect to the file extension, because if somebody uploads something, converting them and removing to an Lscript operation through pure Pythoning operation, okay, because, there, if you remember, we create a hierarchy, like, for
Krish NAik: PDF one folder, for TXT one folder, for Markdown one folder. Okay, and inside that, you will be having your respective extensions,
Krish NAik: For whatever the files that you are uploading.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now few flag variables initially, like the document ID, capture it, I'm all making it none. Okay? But later on, I'm, I'll be updating them.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, I'm checking if the catcher service is true or not, the service is available or not. If it is available, then we will try to look from the… we will compute the document ID, okay, and that document ID, we are logging it. Okay, if the catcher service exists.
Krish NAik: So, we will simply say the catch hit condition is true, so again, that information, I am printing it, and then we'll be loading it directly from the catcher. Okay, so chunks and the embeddings part.
Krish NAik: So, now, based on this condition, if captured data is equal to true, we'll be picking up from the chunks, and so these are basically the keys.
Krish NAik: Okay? Champs and embeddings, so these are basically the keys, from S3 data will be picking it up. And finally, we're returning catch8 is equal to true, fine.
Krish NAik: Now, the cushion part, if catcher is not available, then comes your normal strategy. Like, you will be performing your embedding operation, and your,
Krish NAik: embedding, chunking, all those operations according to the docklink definition that we have done. The hybrid chunking implementation.
Krish NAik: Alright, so generate embeddings and everything. Now, once everything are done, and if your catcher service is available, the idea is to save all this information. Okay, and this catchy is not with respect to Redis, again, I'm repeating.
Krish NAik: This is… with respect to what? Where I'm saving this, catchy, quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: In the chat.
Krish NAik: Everyone?
Krish NAik: Where I'm saving my document catches up with S3, okay? So don't get confused here.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, then, preparing a few metadata, for our main document, document ID, original, file name, upload timestamp, these things also will be available in your estimate, okay, and I'm saving all these things in one.
Krish NAik: Now, Mitesh is asking, radius for query catcher? Correct.
Krish NAik: And S3 for document catcher. Now, Monmouth is asking, document S3, embedded.
Krish NAik: Don't think about embeddings radish. See, embeddings, even I'm saving it in S3, but with respect to query and response, those things.
Krish NAik: I am actually saving it in Redis, okay? The query and response for your rag, as well as for your SQL one.
Krish NAik: Holy cow.
Krish NAik: Now, finally, like, saving the chunks and embedding, so that's why catch a service.saving those things, that comes into the picture. So, once these are done, automatically they will be uploaded into your S3. Okay, if you have selected the backend storage as S3, otherwise locally.
Krish NAik: In your, I think, whichever folder.
Krish NAik: Here, inside your data folder, inside this cache chunks, you'll be having… okay, so this is the hash ID. Inside this hash ID, we'll be having chunks.json, embeddings.npy, okay, and metadata.json. So all these things are for this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so once these things are shipped, now, finally,
Krish NAik: This is the logic, like, I remember the last class, people asked me a lot of times that, okay, if the catcher hit was true for the document service, why you were uploading it? Okay, now here, storing in PineCon, always, even on catcher hit, in case VectorDB was created, okay? Now, this was the mean. If…
Krish NAik: to the VectorDB was key. Now, this is the part where you can add your own logic. It means that if you feel the document
Krish NAik: service that I have, okay, if the catch-up condition is true, you don't need to upload the document.
Krish NAik: But for that, you need to really have a check.
Krish NAik: based on some type of metadata filter in your existing Pinecone, namespace.
Krish NAik: Okay? I hope everybody understands what I mean.
Krish NAik: Because in your metadata, you are actually saving an information with respect to the files.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, again, you can do a check, and in the chat.
Krish NAik: that particular criteria fulfills, you can see that, okay, then upload the vectors.
Krish NAik: If the condition through metadata filtering, it says that, okay, simply the condition fails, okay, then upload it. So, that's why. So, this is where you can bring your own logic, because in my case, I'm always uploading it to Pinecone, because it is not required, I feel.
Krish NAik: You have the unique hash, you have the find name.
Krish NAik: If you have these two things, simply, like, you… those checks.
Krish NAik: Yes or no.
Krish NAik: Yes or no, guys, tell me. Because this part, you can actually do the modification. So that's why I'm very specifically telling. And this part actually should be modified.
Krish NAik: All right, now comes the smart catch-in validation part. So, when a new document comes, so create the rack catcher. Okay, now, if this is a new document and not from the catcher, okay, so in that particular condition, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: If not catch a hit condition, the query catcher and the query catcher service. Okay, so all these conditions I am checking. Finally, if I need to delete something, okay, because the invalidation, catcher feature is also important, so for that, I have done the implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so sometimes I delete it if existing is available, and then again I add it. So, now I feel that this is handy sometimes, and generally with respect to any type of catch-based implementation, you need to add
Krish NAik: Smart catching validation also, because every time, I don't think it will fall into the catching validation. It's less than 5%.
Krish NAik: More than 70% of the time, the invalidation condition arises.
Krish NAik: Alright, then, some information with respect to file size, total tokens…
Krish NAik: And in UPIC, what are the metadata that I am actually saving? So here you can see from UPIC.upic context update current span. Okay, so here, document, upload, extension, catch ahead, the entire metadata dictionary that I had, that I have picked up.
Krish NAik: And I have created one, so file name, file size, format, file extension, length of the chunks, total tokens, catch it.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, if I don't have anything or any issue with respect to OPIC, then simply I will say fail to update the OPEC span. So whenever you are hitting and you are making, so I'm calling it a span right now, a live span.
Krish NAik: How many of you know about Lifespan? Even in AGI, it will come.
Krish NAik: A-S-G-I.
Krish NAik: How many of you know ASGI?
Krish NAik: or W-L-G-I.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: If you have worked with FastGP and Flask. WSGI was the old standard, but right now, everybody had moved to ASGI. Asynchronous.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: I'm talking about ASGI, asynchronous Server Gateway Interface.
Krish NAik: Okay, asynchronous server gateway interface.
Krish NAik: That is the full form. Previously, it was Web Server Gateway Interface. Generally, people who have worked with Flask, you know… in Flask, you've followed a WLGR.
Krish NAik: But right now, I think from Vast API, mutually it has moved to AHGI. You can do a lot of other tasks also, WebSocket, SSE, server sentiments. Okay, it's much better and much more advanced in a single connection, you can do a lot of tasks.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think I'll be talking… when I'll be talking about mangam, then I'll be repeating that stuff. Right now, I do it, if you're not familiar.
Krish NAik: Alright, then determining your backend storage, so based on my config, okay, so where to save that? So, initially, the initialization will be done, and later on, it will be picked up from our ENV.
Krish NAik: And then, returning all those information, so the return status, in your API that you will be seeing. Okay, now this is the actual fast API response for your upload route that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally comes your validation error and any exception that I get.
Krish NAik: Then comes slash query slash documents, so this is a direct query operation on top of your documents.
Krish NAik: Now, this query not only retrievable, so generation is also added here.
Krish NAik: So, that's why I'm looking, first of all, my global here, the one is the RAT service, whether my RAT service is available or not. If the RAT service is available, then fine, we can move to the query validator.
Krish NAik: Anybody remembers what was… query validator.
Krish NAik: So here, I was actually, have checked that if the question is available or not, and here I kept that the minimum length of the cushion should be 3, the maximum should be 1000 characters. In that way, I've added these things.
Krish NAik: So, the question, because right now, wherever you are working with a query, here are a lot of things that can be done, because right now, I've taken a sample condition, but later on, any type of task that you want to do, like query transformations, those things can be added here also, any core functionality that you want to add.
Krish NAik: So this is the main route, the query docs.
Krish NAik: Alright, validating the inputs and output, okay, so then comes check if the service is initialized or not, if the service is available.
Krish NAik: Then comes directly generating our answers. To generate our answer, I need the actual question, or the query that comes from the user, selecting my top K. Then comes our namespace from VectorDB, selection that I have taken, which is the default one.
Krish NAik: If you want to, print out your sources, the actual retrieve chance, so that condition is equal to true that I have kept it. Now, again, all these things, if you want to keep it in UPIC,
Krish NAik: Alright? So, for that, I have kept it. So, in a specific span, it means that whenever I'm calling or hitting this particular API, so OPIC will be tracking all this particular information.
Krish NAik: So, that's why this particular file increased to a lot of lines, because for everything you have it.
Krish NAik: Because whenever I'm doing the selection, all this opaque things, I can actually keep it in a separate file, and I can reduce. Because right now, I think in this file, you have close to 1300 lines of code. Okay, so if I want to actually make it smaller, what are the things that I can do? First of all, I can,
Krish NAik: Keep all my, exceptions in a separate file.
Krish NAik: all these OPIC things in a separate file. Okay, so in that way, I can actually reduce it, but I'm not done those optimizations, but in actual production, we'll be keeping things much more in a modular standard.
Krish NAik: Alright, then this entire thing comes from OPEC, okay, and then finally, again, OPEC fails, and finally, if your route fails. So, all those exception conditions that is,
Krish NAik: Coming here, then comes slash document. Now, this is… slash document only tells you
Krish NAik: The available documents in that particular
Krish NAik: continue, startup. It means that always remember, this route won't be exactly correct, because this route
Krish NAik: It's just, like, a warm and start. It means that the containers can't die.
Krish NAik: So, initially, right now, I know my documents are having a persistent storage, but actually, that information, I'm not saving it anywhere. So, actually, when you are doing it in a serverless environment, it's a good practice that you can take a separate DB.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in that give you can get that information. So, what happens in our case? So, right now, as this is serverless, and if your container dies, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Do you think that this information with respect to slash documents will be available?
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Simply tell me.
Krish NAik: Will it be available?
Krish NAik: Okay? So that's why I'm, also telling that the con part.
Krish NAik: Because if you are working, you have to maintain
Krish NAik: like, some type of DB, entire DB, you need to take the reference. It means that whenever you are hitting the API, the serverless, configuration, your cold start will take place. And during that cold start, even this reference.
Krish NAik: with respect to documents should be there. Because right now, in my case, after every, I can say, like, if the container dies, this slash documents will actually show you zero.
Krish NAik: But, actually, the files are there where? In your S3.
Krish NAik: Okay, but I'm not maintaining that particular relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it will be a good practice if you can actually save this particular information also. Because if you have a dedicated cluster, then it is not a problem. But for serverless applications, really, you need to track a lot of things.
Krish NAik: Because it comes with a cheaper solution, but yes, a lot of other things that needs to be configured.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is the slash route, and generally, like, this will be taken care of. So right now, if I say slash documents and list documents, so from here, it will be doing the listing of the documents.
Krish NAik: Based on the path that I'll be having, the upload directory.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in your S3 as well as in your local, okay, so wherever, whichever is your upload directory, based on that, it will throw you that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now then comes, simple stats. Now, the stats is much more about, query stats, as I can see here. So here you can see the Global SQL service and the Query Catcher service. Okay, now, these are much more…
Krish NAik: from your Redis information, that you have. Because either SQL service and the query catcher service. Okay, this is not from the actual S3, so those capture statistics, if you want, but that you can actually hit it, and based on that, it will return the result.
Krish NAik: Okay, so as I can see, okay, so here,
Krish NAik: the total… the count of uploaded documents, okay, so if you want to really get from the upload directory the total number of files that you have, then pending SQL queries count, if you want.
Krish NAik: Okay… Then comes your query cache statistics. Okay, so that also that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, here, cost estimates according to the four type of keys that I have in my Redis. So, these are the four Redis keys. So, for that, estimated pricing based on GP24 rule that I have taken. But this is not an actual
Krish NAik: Cost…
Krish NAik: Tracking implementation, because for cost tracking, you need a separate module, a proper dedicated module, to do the tracking of that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so…
Krish NAik: So these are all the written type of my stats, so that's why this is the stats part.
Krish NAik: So here you can see in the return type, the total number of documents, the SQL pending queries, the service is available or not. Then comes your query catch stats, the system is up or not, the Python version.
Krish NAik: Then with respect to your rack configuration, what is the chunk size, chunk overlap, max file size, then comes your Redis configuration.
Krish NAik: time to live for your cache, RAG, embedding sickle, so these are the actual keys. Okay, and what are the TTL for each of them? Because for some, I have kept 24 hours, for some, I have kept, like, 7 days, so all those configurations, I'm just loading up in my stats.
Krish NAik: Now, this is slash catches or stats, this is much more about that S3 part. As you can see, document total and total size. These type of information, if you want to get it, again. Now, see, generally, stats and other things is much…
Krish NAik: Helpful, actually, for developer perspective.
Krish NAik: If you're actually creating a dashboard in those cases, I feel that through this route.
Krish NAik: It becomes much more easier with respect to time to track in your any system, how many documents are coming in total. Okay, so for those reasons, I have taken the simple, examples with respect to the catch stats.
Krish NAik: S3 stats, ready stats.
Krish NAik: Then finally comes your cache clearing. Now, this is your catcher clearing, it means this is your Redis implementation. Okay, so here you are actually clearing the S3 as well as the Redis. It means that if you don't pass anything in the argument of your route.
Krish NAik: by default, both the things will be cleared out. But if you keep the keys, for example, your RAG SQL embeddings, then based on that, it will be doing that particular deletion.
Krish NAik: So, but before deleting, we have to check that the service is available, so that's why I get that global variables.com, so we will check the catcher service is available. If it is available, then first of all, clearing your S3. Okay, then comes, ready square. By default, it will always be false.
Krish NAik: when we are actually looking into the service, then we will file later. If Redis is not available to your system, if Redis is available, then we'll be clearing based on the previous. So, this is the first all, and this is a stash Redis implementation. If you use a different Redis, again, this implementation will change.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it actually depends upon the library. So right now, it is the upstash Redis package.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, this is done. Okay. Now, these are the catcher query stats for our… okay, because,
Krish NAik: I have… first, I kept all the stats in both, but later part, I…
Krish NAik: keep the… your ready stats in a separate meeting. Because I feel that in a single route, it's a bad practice to keep both the things.
Krish NAik: So, one, route that I kept would live for S3 first.
Krish NAik: And Redis, and later on in this one, it's much only about the Redis part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you can see here, rag responses embedding. So directly, this part is where the query catches stats, you can actually get it. This information is only about your Redis, and nothing more.
Krish NAik: That's why here I'm looking for the
Krish NAik: query catch a service. It means that only for those 4 keys, and based on those 4 keys, it will return the results.
Krish NAik: Okay, here's I told you that, Redis part, really, I feel that OPEC takes a lot of,
Krish NAik: I can say, and the… Which part that,
Krish NAik: your exception. For exception, you can create a dedicated file, and for OPIC. In that way, you can decrease the line of code mesh.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is one. Finally comes catching, clearing the catcher, alright.
Krish NAik: Again, because that implementation is same as that S3, and later on, I'll get it. Now, this is the part where you want to delete all of your vectors from your vector database, because that particular feature, also, we have it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, whenever you are deleting your vector, the main parameter in Timecone is basically the namespace.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I've not added that particular feature of deleting an index. Okay, if you feel that, because this is… that is much more text, I can say, like, destructive operation. I've not kept it, but if you feel in your case… because most of the times, we keep it.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if you really want to do a reset operation, okay, so, like, clear, reset.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, can anybody tell me what is the difference between clear or a reset operation?
Krish NAik: Simple terms, with respect to VectorDB, if you have worked in your organization, so…
Krish NAik: Because I know, Miji, you guys have done some type of work with respect to that, that's why I'm asking.
Krish NAik: If I say clear and reset.
Krish NAik: what will be the major difference between those? Clear means simply we're deleting all the vectors. What is the meaning of reset?
Krish NAik: Clear means, only data deleted, alright. Reset means?
Krish NAik: A reset means, correct. Methage, it's reset about configuration. For example.
Krish NAik: Whenever I'm doing the testing, just think about, I started with OpenAI 1536.
Krish NAik: Okay, now once you have built that index, you cannot change 1536.
Krish NAik: So, generally, you have to do a reset operation. It means that, again, you have to do the reinitialization of that.
Krish NAik: I hope you get.
Krish NAik: Once you have created any index, suddenly you cannot change that particular, I can say, your dimension.
Krish NAik: So that's why, whenever you are creating an index, it asks you, what is the dimension?
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's what that reset. Reset means delete with your configurations. There, generally, if you want to change the region of your index, all those things that can be done. Yes, reset means pretty much creating a new version of the
Krish NAik: index.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that's why, like, right now, I don't have a reset operation, but again, we keep it. For developers, I feel that is very much handy, because we always test out with different type of dimensions.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Okay, then again, this particular service with respect to… and right now, this implementation that I have delete all vectors, okay, now this is purely based on Pinecone. In Pinecone, I have that, where I pass the namespace.
Krish NAik: So here, only one important parameter, which is namespace by default that I have kept it. Later on, in EY, I have kept the option, if you have a different namespace.
Krish NAik: Because in my case, it's default, okay? So, but if you're not using a default, if you have given a custom name, in that case, you can directly pass it through the Swagger UI.
Krish NAik: It, based on that, it will be deleting all the vectors.
Krish NAik: But right now comes slash query.
Krish NAik: what was… slash query.
Krish NAik: slash query was basically the unified query. So, where a simple keyword routing, based on keywords, if you remember, your unified router file was there, where was that unified router?
Krish NAik: Your routing service?
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is your… based on keywords. I used to route.
Krish NAik: Okay, so where the query will go. So, now, that's why here I am, first of all calling that, so, dev unified query. I'm checking my RAT service and SQL service are available or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's my global initialization, then with a try and check that I… Now, this information also I want to track at an OPEC, so that's why that OPIC function is that I've kept it. Now, here, based on the decision, because this is the actual variable, that will be updated, so if route is equal to is equal to SQL, okay, so…
Krish NAik: And then, finally, the other route will be with respect to your RAG service. So, both the services that I am actually checking, first upon.
Krish NAik: Now, if the SQL service is available, this is the part with respect to generation of your actual SQL. So, first of all, here, you know that SQL generation, two steps. First of all, generate the SQL.
Krish NAik: But firing the SQL in your database is not important, because it's a two-step thing, because here, I've taken a Boolean for that particular approval.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why that generates SQL for approval, first I'm calling it. If auto-approved SQL is equal to true, then even the execution of the approved query, that will be taken into case. And for every generated SQL, a unique query ID, I used to generate that.
Krish NAik: If the execution fails, simply throw the exception that you will be getting, and based on that, update the result and throw.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simply, like, otherwise, this is the part with respect to return for approval, because in your return type, directly, you'll be getting the query ID in your FastAPI response. So that's why through that query ID, again, you can go to the approval route, and manually you can approve that, and you can get your results.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if the route type is equal to document, what will happen? It will go to your RAG service, and it will…
Krish NAik: give you the rag result in simple terms. There is nothing else here.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Majorly, this is done. Okay. Then, okay. Now, I have very specific routes for SQL, if you remember. One was slash query slash SQL slash generate. Now, this is only the generation of the SQL through this route that you can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, this is also… I'm tracking through OPIC, okay, so that I have kept it. Now, here, actually, the mean call is an LLM. Okay, through LLM, you decide what is the… from your natural language to SQL generation, that particular result that you can track.
Krish NAik: Here, again, we have that approval one, because it's actually the same implementation, if you really look into, based on your
Krish NAik: Slash query, which is the unified query route.
Krish NAik: But, if you want to do things in a separate way, so for that, this particular route. Otherwise, the purpose is the same. I hope everybody gets that. So, it's just a bifurcation, because every time, you…
Krish NAik: doing slash variable. Directly, if you want to use the SQL feature, then why to take that added? I can overstep our routing part.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: Then comes, I think the SQL generation part I have already told. Then comes the SQL execution. Okay, like, once the SQL. Now, for execution, what is the most important parameter that you need?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me, guys, even in the quote, I can see.
Krish NAik: What is the… how we can do the actual execution?
Krish NAik: through the query ID.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that, first of all, when you generate the SQL, for that particular query, a query ID will be generated. Then, if you don't do an auto-approval, you pick up the query ID, you pass it, and then you do the execution.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, through this, particular, again, execute approved query, that is the main one, and based on that, I'll be returning the results.
Krish NAik: Now, now this is the slash SQL slash query pending. Okay, now, if… by default, you are telling that, don't approve any queries. It means that the Boolean condition is by default for auto-approval is false.
Krish NAik: Then, for all the queries that you are passing, the natural language queries that you are passing to the system, for every query, a unique query ID that will be generated. Now, all that information will be available under this pending. So, you can actually list all the pending SQL queries.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, you can use your AWAB route, which is the execute one.
Krish NAik: First, look into the pending queries, and based on those pending query IDs, you can do the execution of those SQL queries.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Then comes initialization of the services, now…
Krish NAik: This is a simple initialization, as you can see, pretty much a global one, embedding service, so where I'm actually checking.
Krish NAik: What is my upload directory, catcher directory? So here you can see, first of all, I'll be making a few directories. Why this is important? This is for my Lambda environment.
Krish NAik: How many of you understand that?
Krish NAik: If my Lambda container dies, Can I say that with that, my folders will also die?
Krish NAik: whatever the folders that I have pulled.
Krish NAik: Might catch a directory and upload directly, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, guys, tell me.
Krish NAik: Because as we are working with serverless.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in serverless, you have to handle this, because I know that every time I contain a task, so I told you, so my document service will always show zero.
Krish NAik: Whenever it starts. But actually, the files will be there initially.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for that, you can use a database to maintain that particular mapping and relationship. So that's why I'll be creating an upload directory and a catcher directory every time. Whenever you hit your lamina, okay, these things will be getting created.
Krish NAik: And then logging all the information. Okay, so then checking that OPIC is available or not. Now, generally what happens, sometimes, you might see that in Woopik, if you have manually not created the project.
Krish NAik: Okay, you might get an error. So, generally, to handle that error, I kept this old SKD in system sta- like, standard in, standard out, basically, in this case.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, I feel that it's a good practice in Europic whenever you are actually passing anything. So, for example, if I show you my config.py, where is CCCC config, config, config, yes, config, config.
Krish NAik: Because, actually, when you are testing sequentially, but in production, this particular project, like, whatever the name of the project that you are passing. So here, the OPEC project name. So, always create it manually.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I feel that sometimes with respect to your deployment, if you don't have the permission, you cannot create the custom feature.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's a good practice, always keep the project before and open, then automatically everything will be logged on, otherwise you'll be getting that particular error. That, and if you're getting the error, it means that it will be tracked.
Krish NAik: But the configuration will be different. So, in Opaque, everything gets cracked in the default one. Default.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that in your default project, everything will be getting tracked.
Krish NAik: But…
Krish NAik: like, I know most of you want it in your custom project name, in that way you can do the entire segregation for later on.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Now, the next one that I have.
Krish NAik: is the initialization of my OPEC. Okay, all those services, so if the services are enabled or not, so all those checks that comes into the picture, you can see. OpenAPI, vector service.
Krish NAik: RAT surveys, SQL surveys, query catcher surveys, all those service checks that I am doing. So, generally, like, this is taking so many lives.
Krish NAik: Now, if you remember, I told you, these three lines, if you are actually doing your local testing, please
Krish NAik: uncommon thing. Right now, as we are doing the deployment in Lambda environment, this is not required.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this initialization, I'll be doing it through a mango. Okay, so that's why, for local, please uncomment and then do the execution. I hope everybody remembers, in class.
Krish NAik: We uncommitted this when we were doing our local testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, but for your deployment, you don't need to mention this one. So, whenever you are, defining, okay, an event very specifically, so it's a good practice that you should tell when your application should start. So, during the startup, all this initialization service data will check.
Krish NAik: So, if you actually don't uncomment this line, you will… won't get any logging information in your local.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's the only difference. Then comes app on event shutdown, so finally getting this particular information in your log. Okay, async def shutdown event, and this is our main UVCon startup application.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this file is really big, but again, to a certain level, the optimizations can be done, and it can be reduced close to 700 to 800. That is the maximum level that you can do, not more than that.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the core functionalities will be there.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, the next file that I want to discuss is your Lambda handler.
Krish NAik: Where is the Lambda handler file?
Krish NAik: This is the file, okay? All right.
Krish NAik: Now, already about, I think, here I can open PYPI, mango.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a package widely used for AWS. Lambda-based events? Okay, now this is the package even I am using. It means that directly a FastAP application cannot execute it in a Lambda environment.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you need an adapter for that, and Mangum is the adapter.
Krish NAik: So, this manum is an adapter for running ASGI applications. I hope ASGI, guys. So, this is the one that I was talking about, asynchronous server gateway interface.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: for your AWS Lambda to handle function URLs, API gateway, anything that you are working with.
Krish NAik: application load balancer, okay, then comes your Lambda agent, anything that can be taken care through this particular adapter. So a direct deployment cannot be done in Lambda. If you try to think directly, I can do the execution. It is not possible. Manually, you have to pass what are the events that, on every call, that needs to be handled.
Krish NAik: directly, biology for, that is for the direct execution. Chanika break, let me just complete, because after the break, I want to do the deployment, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, see, this file is very, very small. Okay, so if you really look…
Krish NAik: So, right now, input is Mangum. Okay, like, I know people working with AWS in production. With Python, you guys have used Mangum. Okay, but if you have not worked, okay, only further. Now, here I have taken an oas.environment root path, so…
Krish NAik: Right now, this functionality is not required, because this, I kept it very specifically for API Gateway service, because right now, in our application, we are not using, but if you're working with API Gateway, I think everybody who has previously learned, you have to create routes there, very specifically.
Krish NAik: So that's why I created one route slash prod. But right now, I'm not working with API Gateway, so this is not useful to us.
Krish NAik: Then comes creating your temp directory. Now, these temp directories are for your document catches service. Okay, it means that for your doc… when you upload the document, first it will be available inside slash temp slash uploads in your Lambda container.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why this particular condition, oas.makeDirectory exists is equal to true conditions.
Krish NAik: Now, from here, from app.main import app, initializing the service, as you can see, here I am actually looking into my entire initialization of this. So, all these logs, you can directly see it were in your AWS CloudWatch logs.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, defining our Magnum. So here, what, the mangum adapter? Simply, I have initialized the mangum, and here I have passed my fast API initialization, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Can you see this app that I'm inputting directly, I passed my Fast API app here. And here, lifespan, here I can keep it auto also, but right now I've kept it off right now.
Krish NAik: Now, this part again, right now, not required the API gate to be a base path. I'm not working with the API gateway service. Otherwise, if I'll be using, then slash broad that I have kept it. Okay, this root thing that I'm directly passing it here.
Krish NAik: Then, initially, by default, the service initialization, it will be false. Okay, then once…
Krish NAik: I hit my, main initialized service. Okay, so by… whenever by default, it will be false. When you hit, and it will get the access to your environment variables, then only it will turn to true. So if anything is missing, through this, you can actually have that checked.
Krish NAik: Now, def handler, even at the context, so the Lambda handler with lazy service initialization. Okay, because everything in Lambda is pretty much through a, I can say, a lazy load operation that goes on.
Krish NAik: So, the services are initialized on the first request.
Krish NAik: To avoid a 10-second init timeout, okay? So here, all my global service, anything that I have passed it, everything I have passed it here.
Krish NAik: all those services, close to 10 services that I have in my application. Now, if services are not initialized, simply initialize the service, and this particular flag variable, I'm making it as true, and finally return the handler.
Krish NAik: Which is for Magnum. Okay, so there's 4M that I have.
Krish NAik: Generally, so, on top of your fast app, you just need 3 to 4 lines of code through which you handle it in your AWS Lambda.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, this has to be done in any environment, whether you are working with
Krish NAik: I think, you know, GCP web step functions, I think, okay, or whether you are working with Azure functions, they're also…
Krish NAik: Okay, but, yes, the packet changes with respect to… AWS is the mangam one.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, Abhishek, man-gum is necessary, because directly you cannot run a FastAP application in a Lambda environment.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: through Mangum.
Krish NAik: I run the FastAPI application, because every lambda, there you need to pass what is your startup event, what is your shutdown event.
Krish NAik: Okay, and initially here, that's why I mentioned that lifespan, if you remember.
Krish NAik: Okay, so where is my London? So here, this lifespan definition that needs to be taken care of. You can keep it auto also, but right now I've kept it on.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the core one. Now, in the next part, with respect to the deployment optimization, I think this file, even I pushed it. Okay, so, as I told you, that two-way deployment file, you can actually go through this file. What was the main purpose as I was
Krish NAik: doing it, and I was testing it. So, like, even for me, the base image took a lot of time, to actually do the build. Okay, so you can actually check all those summaries, because this, I directly used Claude, I think. Okay. And right now, as I was testing.
Krish NAik: Yesterday, 4.6 got launched. How many knew about that?
Krish NAik: Yes, Opus 4.6 got launched yesterday.
Krish NAik: I read about it, I know that. This week, I have done a very heavy testing of Kimi…
Krish NAik: 2.5. Very much heavy testing.
Krish NAik: And I will say, really, it's up to the mark with Sonnet 4.5, very, very close, at a very cheap price. Like, if you guys really want to do the testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the money that I've spent, I feel it's worth it. Like, Claude is very costly, that's why my preference with Claude is only when
Krish NAik: If something is very complex, it needs a lot of reasoning, then… For simple type of tasks.
Krish NAik: up to the mark, because I've been using GLM also, 4.7. GLM is okay, okay.
Krish NAik: good for basic stuff, but the intelligence level is really low, okay? But this week, testing with Kimi really, I feel it's up to the mark. Because I think within the next
Krish NAik: a few weeks, Sonnet 5 will also get launched. In the community, that's the workaround, and I know once Sonnet 5 came, then again, Kimi will be below that. But for now, you can give a direct hit to it with Sonnet 4.5 and Kiln.
Krish NAik: Alright, which one, Aniroth?
Krish NAik: Like, I've been working with open source GLM 4.7 Flash is also good. Like, that also, I have tested this one.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, not Kimi. Kimi, guys. Guys, be active in LinkedIn, at least. Kimi, this one. Like, they have a dedicated Kimi, for CLI, but this is the one, Kimi.
Krish NAik: 2.5. They have a visual intelligence, and really, I can say the visual intelligence is good. I can compare it with,
Krish NAik: What I can say, like, OpenAI. So, if you generally… I always look into the LML stats leaderboot, you guys already know it. I always say, you'll check the stats.
Krish NAik: So, I spent the money, so I will look into, like, what are that type. So, here, in the open source community, now Kimi is at the top, so I did the testing, and really, it's good, guys. Okay, now, this is the actual leaderboard that you have.
Krish NAik: Gemini 3, again, I'm not a fan of Gemini, though… Like, it's not mine.
Krish NAik: OPA's really good, this is new, so right now the testing in one day it cannot come up. People will do a lot of testing on a benchmark, then I know it will come up, actually. GPT 5.2, again, this is good, I can say. I've worked with Codex.
Krish NAik: So I can… and… but in the open source one, this is the best one. So this Kimi 2.5 and JLF 4.7, both are open source, so right now I'm working
Krish NAik: with these two open source LLMs.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that going forward, the intelligence level of open source LLMs are actually good.
Krish NAik: Okay, because really for initial testing. Because going forward, I feel that in my next batch, I can use Kimi 2.5.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really good one. You guys can also test it out, at least. I think they have a 7 days…
Krish NAik: Free. Okay, after that, they will be charging. So, for Kimi, you can actually test it out. A 7-day trial is…
Krish NAik: Or if you have Open Router, it's everywhere it's available. Through Open Router also, you can access it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, let's talk about our… Ugh, mean what?
Krish NAik: Because… let's go for a break. Okay, now… I think after the break.
Krish NAik: We'll be starting the deployment phase.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what are the changes that need to be done? Because the core application is done, I've just divided it into a two-way approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, one for your voice-level dependencies, one for your application-level dependencies. So the first video will take a lot of time, close to, like, 20 to 25 minutes, but once your base image is built, everything will be much faster.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we'll be talking about that.
Krish NAik: Now, is Kimi, what exactly testing you did? I was actually working with a few core databases with respect to Kimi.
Krish NAik: Then I was working with a few Hugging Fields models where I asked very specific tasks.
Krish NAik: With respect to MS Marco testing, okay, so a lot of other tests that I try to do, like, Opus always passes those things, so… but Opus is very costly, like…
Krish NAik: $5 for 1 million tokens, like, very, very costly. Even, like, the Claude family, I can say the intelligence is good.
Krish NAik: Because after Cloud, I feel that, you have 5.2 from OpenAI.
Krish NAik: And Gemini 3, I don't know. Sometimes it works, sometimes it doesn't.
Krish NAik: I really, like…
Krish NAik: even with their paid plan, I feel that. Because my credit card is always attached with their main one, but I feel…
Krish NAik: Gemini not up to the mark. Only for learning is good.
Krish NAik: But in production, I know people are actually using it.
Krish NAik: But really, with respect to responses… because whenever you are building with RAC, guys, always remember, don't spend a lot on your LLMs. It's a very, very bad practice.
Krish NAik: Never select go with this option.
Krish NAik: You should focus on how to improve your returable quality.
Krish NAik: Much more.
Krish NAik: If your retrieval quality is good, if your reacting quality is good, okay, I can say the results will be. You never need a good end.
Krish NAik: Because by default, I've seen many people directly working and passing Gemini 3 data. But it's not RAG. In RAG, the core thing as a developer, you need to work in on the retrieval quality, on your chunking quality.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: these are the core things that… but it's not that LLM will solve… it's not about L&M music, that's why.
Krish NAik: Yes, right now in my system, I think for Project 3, I have taken the Voyage, embeddings.
Krish NAik: Voyage AI, I think everybody knows about Voyage, so many times I've told you in class also. So, this time… I can use the Voyage AI embeddings also, but I think it's better to go with the re-ranker, because the MS Marco re-ranker is not really up to the mark.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And generally… Now, from here, rerang 2.5 that I was actually planning to use in your project 3.
Krish NAik: But, you can do this. Now, Voyage AI, widely used because this is a product from Mongo.
Krish NAik: Mongo, that's why people use it. So, I think in the next one, they have their dedicated embedding models, they have their re-ranking models, okay.
Krish NAik: But not with respect to LLMs, that's why. Okay, for LLM, we'll be using OpenLang. But this is for Project 3 adapting.
Krish NAik: This… they have a limited pay, limited trial.
Krish NAik: It's not, like, unlimited, because this is a paid service, so… but for our initial testing, it will be good.
Krish NAik: OpenClaw, really, like, open claw, so many times the name changes. The project is on hype right now.
Krish NAik: But again, agents and agents, I know these things again.
Krish NAik: Because after, right, you are talking about open cloth.
Krish NAik: Arthur OpenClaw, the other project that got famous, I think yesterday, was NanoClaw.
Krish NAik: A claw will come.
Krish NAik: That's why I don't love, because there is… it's not about research there.
Krish NAik: You're just hosting your own custom agent, so generally, if you're trying to build your own personal EIS system, then only it's good.
Krish NAik: Yes, Claude also released. Coolwork is good, I can say. I have done the testing, and I will say that it's, good. But again, I don't need
Krish NAik: Coolwork.
Krish NAik: In my system, usually everything from terminal that I prefer.
Krish NAik: Because, slowly, slowly, please try to use
Krish NAik: for every developer, like, rather than going to IDE,
Krish NAik: Try to use Terminal much more.
Krish NAik: Because if you… see, if you don't want to spend, use open code. That is the best combination.
Krish NAik: Okay, open code that you can use with EME, I can say it's really a good one. I can see a lot of developers, senior devs, they are enjoying it.
Krish NAik: But, like… In organization, I think most organizations are providing access to OpenAI.
Krish NAik: Lesser with respect to cloud, I feel. Every organization that I feel, everybody is getting that GitHub co-pilot.
Krish NAik: Because everybody is using your main, I can say, GitHub in their organization, for that subscription to every employee, they are providing it.
Krish NAik: Yes, somehow.
Krish NAik: productivity it makes, I can say.
Krish NAik: The workflow, it becomes much faster.
Krish NAik: Because, Mitesh, okay, like, yes, if you have a much more secure, Dolama is also my own preference.
Krish NAik: But Olama, with Olama, that is the thing you can't use OpenAI and Cloud, which are much more enterprise-level stuff.
Krish NAik: You can use open source stuff, that's the thing. And really, Vitesh, like, if you're working with Olama, if your organization have a dedicated hosted GPU-based platform, okay, then, like, please check out the team models. Really, they are good. In open source, GLM was good.
Krish NAik: Because on January 1st week I tested, last week, they, like, give me a change of the key.
Krish NAik: So, please do have a check. I mean, please use the 7-day trial, at least. You are not getting charged. If you don't feel like it's a bad one, simply skip it.
Krish NAik: But do the testing, because…
Krish NAik: That's one. Because with respect to agents, really open claw, Mike was checking that, because my part is much more LLM, right? The stuff I look. Agents, I'm not a fan, that's why I always tell you. Agents are… it will come, it will go.
Krish NAik: Because for everything, adding agents is not a solution. I don't feel if you're actually building a core product.
Krish NAik: If the entire product cannot be based on the agents.
Krish NAik: Probably it can be a part of your product.
Krish NAik: But not an entire project.
Krish NAik: There are Indian LLMs. Who told you? There are no Indian LLMs. IIT has, IT Delhi has, IT Mattress has, even your regional language-based LLMs.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think let's go for a break, and then we will start with the deployment part, okay? Because, only one thing that needs to be created is a ECR part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's start. And,
Krish NAik: Because Krisht asked me to, do that.
Krish NAik: But today, like, a little bit, my health is also not okay because of that.
Krish NAik: Sorry, let me start sharing the clock. By default, where is CLOCK, yeah?
Krish NAik: Because the timings, next month.
Krish NAik: First of all, like, I think tomorrow I'll be releasing a Google form, okay?
Krish NAik: Like, I need a group of students, because for the new batch for US that I was planning. Okay, so from US, at least 3 to 4 guys that I want.
Krish NAik: Okay, who… like, 50% from my site that I'll be putting with respect to the syllabus creation, and 50% from your site that I want, because the requirement in the US market is a bit different as compared to Indian market. They focus a lot on R&D. Indian market, very less R&D, much more about the application part.
Krish NAik: So, like, tomorrow I'll be releasing a form only for US students, because the timing will be morning. I have only two slots, one is a morning slot.
Krish NAik: morning meals, very morning, like, 5.30 or 6 AM that I am planning. Okay, or, like.
Krish NAik: It can be around…
Krish NAik: afternoon 3.30, but 3.30 for US, that time doesn't make any sense, so probably I feel that Indian time, 16. Because I was having a chat with Krish, Krish told, okay, let's do the experiment, so few people from U.S.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because from U.S, only, because number of students I want is less, yeah, so…
Krish NAik: Only specific people, and who feel that, because a morning batch, I know everybody cannot commit it.
Krish NAik: So much more in English, specialized bachelor and planning. So I think next month, 3-4 meetings that I'll be taking, with respect to the syllabus creation part.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, a monthly discussion, because for that.
Krish NAik: few things that I'll be keeping it separate.
Krish NAik: Okay. Any, opinions on factory.ai, Muther, sir? Yes, I have used factory.ai. Factory.ai, have you tested Droid?
Krish NAik: their agentic framework, the coding one, it's really great.
Krish NAik: Even right now, like, this week I have not worked with Droid. Last week, I was working with Droid a lot.
Krish NAik: This week, it was the Kimi week, so I was working with KimiCode.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, every week I…
Krish NAik: change things in mind. So, like, new things are coming up. Factory.ai is really good, I feel, as compared to OpenCode. If you're working with, like, OpenCode, I will say don't use OpenCode.
Krish NAik: Factory Drought AI is much better, their Druid one is much better.
Krish NAik: Yeah, agentic coding architecture, if I see.
Krish NAik: Open, the code is… okay, okay again.
Krish NAik: I'm not a fan of open code, really.
Krish NAik: Because that, planning mode, switching to the build mode, those things are not really great. Droid is great in that.
Krish NAik: Parav, have you heard about BMAD, Method to Develop Projects? Not exactly BMAD, but you can let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, I sorted.
Krish NAik: on your WhatsApp channel, I think you guys have implemented very bad on your WhatsApp channel, even, like, WhatsApp channel, even I am not sure about.
Krish NAik: I think you guys have implemented.
Krish NAik: Like, Mitesh, like, with respect to the technicality, even I don't know which WhatsApp channel are you referring to?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because that says one or others, one, even I'm not sure about.
Krish NAik: Okay, no issue.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, like, once, let's… because I'll be doing multiple rounds of planning for that batch, because this is, like, again, pilot batch, it means that when I do some experiment.
Krish NAik: Okay? I need to dedicate more time. Probably, I will plan that in the end of May or the first week of June.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we have time. So, like, 6 to 8 sessions on people who are interested for them only, because right there, I don't want, like.
Krish NAik: to make, because again, that will be a little bit LLM side and drag side.
Krish NAik: But taking things much more towards the advanced. Because I think from the security perspective also.
Krish NAik: Because when I think about, like, RAG is really an ocean, if you try to do a much more research, like, in the past 2 years, I have understood that.
Krish NAik: Ocean means, like, when you actually need to research, ocean, like, complete.
Krish NAik: And then from enterprise level, actually, we're doing a lot of security stuff that comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: are back as the… okay, guardrail links are there. Okay, much more advanced stuff, when I say.
Krish NAik: When you actually try to build an enterprise.
Krish NAik: stuff, okay. Like, provenance, governance that needs to be maintained.
Krish NAik: your chunk, label, prompt injection, a lot of things that come, that's why. So, those advanced things, because English is different in India, again, it's different as well.
Krish NAik: Okay, timer app, forgot. Thanks, Balaji. Okay, just wait 10 minutes.
Krish NAik: Kreshnight business account, okay, alright. Because even I don't know, like, who has done that.
Krish NAik: I need to inform that Mitesh. Okay, just, you can drop me a mail with some screenshots, I will send it, because I think that is not done by the tech team, it is done by the sales team, just for their own purpose only, that's why.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I will keep it open, but you can see, the idea is not to text
Krish NAik: students who are not familiar, because there, my idea is not teaching RAC,
Krish NAik: are teaching directly LLM from scratch.
Krish NAik: Okay, that won't be my priority. It's much more application and R&D level that I want to take things on.
Krish NAik: See, you have to understand, when you try to create something complex, it becomes much more harder.
Krish NAik: Okay, for me, just think about this project. I started, I think, in January 18th. It's February, it's going to be 10th. It took around, like.
Krish NAik: More than 2 weeks to discuss.
Krish NAik: Okay, because a lot of things, that changes sometimes, based on optimization that I can take it, so…
Krish NAik: It's… take time. So that's why… Jananteja is asking the modern route full-stack generative AI with Agent Taking. In my course, there are only agents, like, nearly, I'm not a fan. I'm much more LLM side, how to work with SLMs much more, because there, you have few things, but again, not on that level.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, really hosting your own LLMs, how to create embedding models.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, those things I want to focus on. So, little bit of R&D stuff.
Krish NAik: It's only important, like, I feel somebody's more than…
Krish NAik: 4 to 5 years of experience, more than that, or architect-level stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, not for freshers, so that's a little bit about your background also, because you students will keep it open, but again, that I feel that everybody should not enroll, then I don't want that. I might say that…
Krish NAik: I could not understand anything.
Krish NAik: So that's why I think tomorrow I'll be releasing the form. And even in, this batch is my first priority, okay? Then comes the other batch that I'll be picking up, probably, from.
Krish NAik: Uds, because data batch also I'm completing from UDS, I will try to get few things… students…
Krish NAik: And then finally, agents 1.0 and 2.2. I will be asking.
Krish NAik: Because I have the entire customer base, I actually asked it from the marketing team, and I have the students' data from Canada, US,
Krish NAik: UK, Australia.
Krish NAik: So, majorly that, I think, the mail's another thing that you'll be getting.
Krish NAik: Posca, Paul, I think Krish will be taking a session, what is the idea? But the entire execution will be done by me.
Krish NAik: Sinivas, I think I got enrolled as an AI pro to see go through real time. Can you suggest me a project?
Krish NAik: Really, I think there are 2 or 3 rack projects out there, the dock rack search, you can check out the voice agent one.
Krish NAik: Because when I look, that is good, if you want to check that.
Krish NAik: few things, because even I have not done the recording. Krishal asked me, probably, like, from your course project, one or two things that I can pick up and I can do the record. Probably I will change the cloud platform, probably from AWS to GCP there.
Krish NAik: Yes, those things, Anoop, I'll be talking about much more the advanced one, because enterprise-level stuff, here I have not kept in this batch much more.
Krish NAik: Azure, I won't be really… from Azure, specific services that I'll be taking up. Because from Azure, the best service that I love is the talk intelligence one within.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from building… working with multimodal rack, that one is good. But take it, blow it in this patch.
Krish NAik: This is much more focused towards, like, AWS and GCP.
Krish NAik: For the advanced one, I'm telling you, like, 50% your inputs that I can take, and 50% from my site that I will pass out.
Krish NAik: So you guys can suggest the topics based on that.
Krish NAik: I can work.
Krish NAik: Okay, Azure AI is such fascinating. Try it in December versus February, create upgrade.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will export that one.
Krish NAik: AWS, I feel that sometimes Azure Doc Intelligence is much better than AWS Tech Strat.
Krish NAik: In some cases, I can say detect outside, but I can say a little bit dominance towards Doc Intelli. Because in production, even I prefer Dock Intelligence much more.
Krish NAik: With respect to AWS stack, then no options. Tech-up chat is good.
Krish NAik: Video indexing Azure is better.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Hmm, correct.
Krish NAik: Either AWS or Azure, based on hyperscaler.
Krish NAik: Oh, no, no, in this batch, I'll be teaching Gartners.
Krish NAik: But not enterprise cartels one, that I'm telling you. Cartels, I'll be talking about that.
Krish NAik: Gardens is easy.
Krish NAik: on the latest, Anthropic, speech going around where software engineering is getting automated, certain aspects I can see of things that will get automated.
Krish NAik: But again, like, a lot of layoffs are taking place right now, so I can say, to a certain extent.
Krish NAik: But in the next 5 years, the landscape will be a lot different.
Krish NAik: purely. If people are not starting with AI, it will become a problem. Adoption in their workflows is the most important one.
Krish NAik: And the main part is right now, validation and evaluation. These two are the things where human comes into the picture. As the intelligence grows.
Krish NAik: that part, I feel that it will take more time.
Krish NAik: The same concept came in, like, LCM, VLJPA, because from… majorly, the good papers that comes around, apart from Facebook AI research, I can say, the FAIR, the… those guys.
Krish NAik: So from there, like, LCM was really a good paper, but again, in practical implementation.
Krish NAik: Not. Again, for VLJPA, they have not open sourced it. Let me see. Once they open sourced, a lot of things will change in the EI lines.
Krish NAik: Alright, Anoop, I will look into Temple won't worry.
Krish NAik: Yes, Anirud, that's the plan.
Krish NAik: Hey guys, just wait for 5 more minutes, okay, then I will start. Have you eat something, just give me 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: I'll be back in free.
Krish NAik: Just give me 5 more minutes, guys, okay? I'll be back in 5.
Krish NAik: Panivas, okay, I will get back to your analysis, just wait.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so… Let's start our discussion.
Krish NAik: I think I need to log into my EWS console.
Krish NAik: Just to be tough.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please log in to your… AWS.
Krish NAik: accounts…
Krish NAik: Whoa.
Krish NAik: Which repo am I cloning?
Krish NAik: Same room.
Krish NAik: no changes with the report text to SQL one only.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, first of all, let me show you my ECR, okay?
Krish NAik: So, I've added one here.
Krish NAik: I think which one? This one is, Lambda depths. Okay, now this is your base image, where I have kept my…
Krish NAik: base image that I'll be building. Okay, so one specific repository for the base image.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, again, it's better to differentiate with respect to the repose. So, one is the OS level, the base image one, then comes our mean Docker image. Okay, so which is, I think, this is the RAT text to SQL Server. What I will do…
Krish NAik: Let me delete all this stuff.
Krish NAik: I will just take a cleaner approach.
Krish NAik: If… okay, now this particular configuration… let me delete this one also.
Krish NAik: Because the first time, it might take 20 to 30 minutes, but going forward, it will reduce to 4 to 5 minutes only.
Krish NAik: Market.
Krish NAik: Now let's… go here… Where is my gitub? Deploy.yme, okay?
Krish NAik: So, in this particular file.
Krish NAik: Can you see here the base image repository, which is the Lambda dev server, okay? And then the ECR repo name, which is the RAT Text2SQL Server, so these two I have deleted, so there are no images right now.
Krish NAik: Then the base image tag that I've kept it, which is 3.12, the same one that I have deleted right now in front of you, that I have shown.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, and then comes your, lambda function. Okay, now this function, I think in the last class, you guys have already created it, so that function is fine, you don't need to do any changes with respect to the function. So directly, we'll be updating the function based on the container.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, what I've done in the last class, I remember, like, somebody was getting that, error with respect to disk space.
Krish NAik: So, this particular line of code that I have added. Now, what is the main purpose?
Krish NAik: to clean up the disk space in my GitHub.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, in GitHub Actions, whenever you are doing any task, it have a very specific disk size. I think it's close to 72G.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm just deleting everything whenever we are starting an operation, just a clean-up operation, so that just because of this size, anything won't fit. In the last class I saved implementation was done by, I think.
Krish NAik: I forgot the guy's name, like, Naveem or someone like that. Okay, so that particular implementation that I have taken here.
Krish NAik: REST piece of code is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, now, setting up Docker, verifying the credentials, logging to your ECR,
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Check and build the built image if needed, so this is actually a check.
Krish NAik: It means that if the base image is not available, then only it will do a build. If it is available, then it won't do the build. So that's why simple check condition, because this is the actual bottleneck of our previous deployment.
Krish NAik: All those DNF install of all the OS-level dependencies used to take a lot of time. Okay, if you remember, these are the main dependencies. Cairo, then comes Pango, free type, Harvard. Okay, now these are based on top links.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why building the base image, you can see, dockerfile.lambda.base.
Krish NAik: Okay, so dockerfile.lambda.base, let me show you dockerfile.lambda.base. So in this file, what I have, first of all, I am selecting my main base image from Docker Hub, okay, and then I'm building my main base image. And here, only the installation with respect to OS-level dependency that I have kept it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, amazon, like, Lambda images are much more based on, I can say, RHEL, Red Hat.
Krish NAik: Enterprise, based, images. Okay, so for that, all this. Only this part, other than that, there is nothing here.
Krish NAik: Only the OS-level things that I have taken care of.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think, yes, Nawavi was there. Yes, that Nawavi last class you shared me, based on that, I have taken that to Navawi
Krish NAik: Okay, now let's get back to our deploy.
Krish NAik: So only this thing has changed in our deployment.
Krish NAik: Rest, everything is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… update the lambda function, it's the same one.
Krish NAik: Okay, based on environment, lambda function… okay, now this part is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to the bucket name, okay, so the bucket name part, again, I will repeat, if you're using a different bucket name, just be sure that it's available in your policy, because in my policy.
Krish NAik: Whereas docs, I think, newdeploy.md, this was the file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, just various… In this file, with respect to your,
Krish NAik: policies here, I've given the S3 resource. So this is the naming convention, ragcatcher.star or ragcatcher.star.star, that I've given it. If you give a different bucket name, just be sure in the S3 policy you are updating it.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, keep something just like rack, catch a bucket, rack cache Talks, Q&A, something like that.
Krish NAik: If you are giving any custom
Krish NAik: names. Okay, I'm not following this, just be sure you are updating this file. In the last class, I think someone was there, like, Rajat was getting there just because of this. So, follow the naming conventions that I have used.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, the rest, I think, most of the things are done. This document I have not updated yet.
Krish NAik: But, I think majorly, rest things are done. With respect to the auto build also, like, what are the steps that will be taken? Okay, so check this document.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want…
Krish NAik: Because in my context, right now, just to explain as requested by many students, share the doc. So, this is the workflow for your piece.
Krish NAik: Base… like, base image detection. GitHub workflow starts, base image exists or not. Okay, if it does exist, pull, catch a base image, build the application, deploy to Lambda. Okay, if it… then building. Now, this is the actual bottleneck, which will take a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so before the deployment,
Krish NAik: I start, what are the things that need to be taken care from your side? First of all, create, this ECR.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: this work. The Lambda Python depths. Create it from the UI, that is also fine.
Krish NAik: I have no issues, because if you really look into, this starting part will be same for anything. Only slash this part will change.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this part, just be sure you created it.
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: This part you need to manually create, so create it from the command line using the command AWSECR. Okay, so you can use that command. Otherwise, manually just create the repository and keep it to yourself.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let me show you the GitHub Actions part also.
Krish NAik: Only one change is required for public release.
Krish NAik: text to SQL… I'm just… okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this branch, actually I was doing the testing, Okay, so in this branch.
Krish NAik: Okay, with respect to that Docker one, okay, so let me just show you, I think yesterday I made…
Krish NAik: This one… CPU only torch, okay?
Krish NAik: Again, I'm showing you this particular commit, because this is another level of optimization that you can do it. Till now, I have not merged the branch to my mean, but I'm showing you, so…
Krish NAik: In your docker.lambda file, okay, so docker.lambda, let me just show you docker… dot lambda.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what I have done, I have just added this one line.
Krish NAik: line number 49. Right now, I am actually in the branch
Krish NAik: optimized one, okay? The… if I show you…
Krish NAik: You can see right now, so the optimized PyTorch CPU branch, okay? So, this is the only one line that needs to be added. Then all those NVIDIA-related libraries
Krish NAik: only be installed.
Krish NAik: if you don't pass this flag, then all those NVIDIA-related libraries, which are actually not required, will be installed into the system.
Krish NAik: Just because of docklinks, I can say more than 30 to 40 packages that got added.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm exactly showing you what is that. I think, if you check…
Krish NAik: doc links, so that's why I'm exactly showing you the commit also.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can you see here?
Krish NAik: But I've taken only this one.
Krish NAik: Because right now, macOS is not required, as I'm… was working. So this is according to the official documentation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I've picked up this, and I have kept it. So whenever the installation of Docklink, so this is the link from where it will pick up.
Krish NAik: Okay? So automatically, it will be taken care of. This is another level of optimization that you can do. I'm telling you, these are the things. So you don't have to do anything, this is done, but I'm telling you, this is a major change.
Krish NAik: that I have done it.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Mao.
Krish NAik: This part also, I have shown you.
Krish NAik: Okay, now with respect to other ones.
Krish NAik: Yes, that is the line, Raul. Only that extra index URL. Rest, everything is done. Target lambda, task root was previously there. Only that one line of CPU build.
Krish NAik: Okay, that you can actually edit.
Krish NAik: I think,
Krish NAik: Just wheat.
Krish NAik: Great.
Krish NAik: Now, if I show you my Docker Lambda again, you will see that
Krish NAik: Where I have done… now, this is the part. Now, this is my main branch. In my main branch, I have not done the change.
Krish NAik: So, that's why, again… okay, so I've just changed the branch right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these two are the CPU-only PyTorch. Now, in that way, the image becomes much more smaller. That is another level optimization with respect to other packages.
Krish NAik: Not a lot of things that can be done.
Krish NAik: So, majorly, the dockling was one of the other bottlenecks.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this, I have done it. Manually, I can just copy-paste it, and I can do that.
Krish NAik: Hmm… now,
Krish NAik: ECR part, everybody, let me just show you the GitHub actions also, once the final change, because if you guys have created the ECR one, no issues.
Krish NAik: You see, okay, sorry, settings… Secret Williams Actions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the unwanted one is this API gateway URL.
Krish NAik: Like last week, again, this is not required.
Krish NAik: In my case, like, last class, I exposed the API key, so I updated it, the OpenAI API key, even the OPC API key, I have updated it yesterday.
Krish NAik: There's three catcher bucket. This also, I think it is a docs Q&A for me. Okay, in your case, just be sure you are following that same naming convention, according to the policy that you have given.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the one.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just delete from here also everything.
Krish NAik: I'm just cleaning up stuff.
Krish NAik: So that…
Krish NAik: It becomes easier. And just be sure you are passing the same name, in your config.yml also, okay? Because…
Krish NAik: If something gets overwritten there, okay, so in your config.y, you'll be having somewhere this one, line number 75, S3 catch a bucket name. Just be sure you are passing the exact same name.
Krish NAik: Okay, so all these things should be same. Here, it should be same.
Krish NAik: Okay, because again, this thing, I can actually update it through Lambda environment.
Krish NAik: Just wait one minute, I'm getting an important call.
Krish NAik: So, guys, just be sure that all this environment stuff is…
Krish NAik: Fine. Okay, from your side, have a check on these links.
Krish NAik: Mmm.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure S3, Cache, ready stuff, whatever the thing that you are passing, it's correct here. Okay, otherwise, I can update it, you know, manually from where?
Krish NAik: the Lambda environment part.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because… But before that, only it's a good practice to take the precautionary steps.
Krish NAik: Lambda… Okay, so if I go here…
Krish NAik: with respect to… what is the name, I think server was the name. Okay, so if I go to my configuration, I have to delete a lot of unwanted things are here, environment variables. So, from again here, okay, so everything that you can update it later on also.
Krish NAik: But for now.
Krish NAik: just be sure you are keeping those things. A lot of environment variables are there, close to 20, few common things with respect to our Lambda environment that I need to pass with you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now, guys, let me know that, once you guys have created this ACR part, because that is the only major change that is required.
Krish NAik: So, once you create it, create it from the UI, but just give the same name, Lambda Python Text. From where you can get the exact name, check deploy.yml.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in deploy.yml, line number… 10.
Krish NAik: See, here I am passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure this is the exact one.
Krish NAik: Only this thing, just create it by yourself.
Krish NAik: Should I reclone? Why reclone? Always do a git pull.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are doing, always do a git pull.
Krish NAik: If you forked it in the morning, it's fine. Right now, I've not done any change.
Krish NAik: Okay? So I will just do one major change, because that Docker build part, even I have not tested it with respect to that dockling part.
Krish NAik: Let me test it right now. Because I think it should work in my local, it was working fine.
Krish NAik: But, let me take that particular commit.
Krish NAik: And I will be updating here.
Krish NAik: I think this is one.
Krish NAik: I think only these 3 lines that need to be copied.
Krish NAik: One is the docker.lambda, this is the actual application, and this is the base one. Okay? So here…
Krish NAik: One is Dutch.
Krish NAik: There's one… where is that line? I think this is the line.
Krish NAik: So, UVIC install…
Krish NAik: So, I've added only the PyTorch wheel for now.
Krish NAik: As you can see, one major change with respect to my Docker Lambda
Krish NAik: But why nothing got detected in my listing?
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think… This part is done.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: Okay, yes. It took a lot of time for the London.
Krish NAik: CPU.
Krish NAik: Okay, guys, so now, once I start doing, you know that the deployment will start.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, let me just click on this, because this will take 20 to 30 minutes.
Krish NAik: Because right now, the base image will take a lot of time. I will just do one thing. So, what do you have to do? Just create the base image ECR, according to the naming standard that I have kept it in deploy.vironment. That's the only one change.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I think text to SQL…
Krish NAik: Okay, if it fails, then again, it's a different thing, but,
Krish NAik: Right now. Now, this part I have added, freeing up disk space, because both the build actually takes a lot of space in your
Krish NAik: Ma…
Krish NAik: GitHub Actions, right? So, right now, can you see here, GitHub Actions size is 72GB, used is 50 GB, available is 23 GB.
Krish NAik: So, right now, based on this particular size, if you cross this, simply you will get an error with respect to your GitHub actions.
Krish NAik: So, everybody, please create your ECR, that's the only thing, and then…
Krish NAik: The major one, you can take my recent Git pull, and you can start your deployment phase.
Krish NAik: Other than that, nothing needs to be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have cleaned up my… everything, like, S3 I have cleaned.
Krish NAik: ECR… both the ECR repos I have cleaned, so everything. So, it's pretty much taken from scratch. So, you guys can let me know. Create that, base image ECR repo, okay, and start the deployment.
Krish NAik: Everybody.
Krish NAik: You have to pass your own ACR1.
Krish NAik: So, if I show you, Rahul, like, I get the automated word, please don't use this.
Krish NAik: Script of building base one.
Krish NAik: So, here that I have kept my account ID, okay, because your URI is always based on that particular account ID, so here I have kept it.
Krish NAik: But, please don't use this particular script. Go to your deploy.yml, and here, the things that are mentioned, if you are creating it, then there is no issue. Once here, login to ECR will be done, then it will be checking from here. So, ENV is Base Image Report Victory.
Krish NAik: This is the main variable that I have.
Krish NAik: In docker.lambda, okay, just wait, in docket.lambda, let me just see, docker.lambda1.
Krish NAik: Because I think, this one…
Krish NAik: the builder stage, docker.lambda.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, I think this is the, like, again, the line that needs to be updated. Just pass your, AWS account ID name. Okay, Rahul, I think that everyone, the line number 80, this particular account ID, just pass it.
Krish NAik: Okay, folks, please have it checked from your actual EPR. So that's why I'm telling this needs to be passed there.
Krish NAik: ECR, ECR, where is… See ya?
Krish NAik: Yeah, so just be sure You copy-paste this same stuff, copy it from here.
Krish NAik: And you can directly, pass it. So this is the tag you will get till this point, and then you can add 3.12.
Krish NAik: This is the other change that is required, thanks for mentioning return.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in my case, it looks like,
Krish NAik: something failed. Okay, let me see.
Krish NAik: Okay, this docklink one is only creating the issue.
Krish NAik: Hmm… EVP install hyphenr requirement extra index URL.
Krish NAik: Because this is what needs to be passed in the measure wheel.
Krish NAik: So, white field, because I feel that the docklink link is fine, just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me check the link of docklink once again.
Krish NAik: strandex URL… Mmm…
Krish NAik: This is the only line change.
Krish NAik: just…
Krish NAik: How to start the build? Just do a git push punam.
Krish NAik: Hey, Jasmine, later on, I will do this particular optimization, okay?
Krish NAik: Just wait. Might take,
Krish NAik: I'm just wait for it now.
Krish NAik: The code base is bigger, it's taking really a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Why it's not recognizing?
Krish NAik: I have done it from the command line, I don't know. This is taking a lot of time, okay? So, I've done it from the command line.
Krish NAik: Now it will stop.
Krish NAik: Later on, I will look into this, because I know this was the solution, but I will check it with my Optimized CPU branch rules.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Where is GitHub, GitHub, GitHub, the obvious… Almighty?
Krish NAik: No, I have, reverted back, because that, ECR build I will check, because I know it should work, but,
Krish NAik: I think hyphen target lambdaTaskRoute needs to be given. Let me check I've done that particular update, because lambda task rules is important here.
Krish NAik: Because what is the root directory of my main lambda? It understands where we are doing the installation of the libraries, that's why I feel Raoul is important.
Krish NAik: Line number 80, docket.lambda.
Krish NAik: Line number 80, docker.lambda, this… not 80, I think 78.
Krish NAik: Right now, I made a new commit, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the base image was found, can you see right now? In the last step, what happened? The base image was not available, so it took time, but this time, the base image was available. So, under 1 minute 50 second.
Krish NAik: That part is done. Now, this was the major bottleneck.
Krish NAik: In our previous deployment. So, keeping the base image in a separate way. Now, your Docker build will directly start, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, all those libraries and other things.
Krish NAik: Because this part, a lot of NVIDIA things that comes, and that is because of that, docklink parameter.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, just let it, then again, I will do the changes and I will test it.
Krish NAik: Because, for today, because this is done, then tomorrow I will start with query transformations.
Krish NAik: CRAG, SRAG, those things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's wait.
Krish NAik: At Leil, this should be faster.
Krish NAik: Because, till the Lambda environment part.
Krish NAik: See, generally Lambda takes around 60 seconds for the function to be updated. A few post-checks are there, so really…
Krish NAik: Pushing the image to…
Krish NAik: PCR, and even, like, I feel that in this particular base image, I can much more optimize your base image. It means that few things with respect to docklings and other things, I keep it installed in one shot there only, so that at least the dependency doesn't come here.
Krish NAik: Right now, you can see this 275 will be reduced to close to 200, once I remove that docklink with the CPU build. Right now, it's not tested that part, I just kept it as a commit, but later on, I will do the testing, once this is done successfully.
Krish NAik: You know, Aniroth, not any specific pages. It comes in the feed only, no?
Krish NAik: You guys can let me know once you have created the base image.
Krish NAik: ACR, and start the deployment. For now, don't use the CPU build of docking, use the normal one. After this, I will do the testing.
Krish NAik: Well, in where I am adding the PyTorch part, where I am adding the PyTorch part.
Krish NAik: It is in your requirement.txt, actually.
Krish NAik: Because in my local, it was working. I will check that with respect to that deployment.
Krish NAik: Well, this is…
Krish NAik: Because we are copying the entire requirement.txt, so…
Krish NAik: that part directly, I can switch it from here, so update.
Krish NAik: Alright, pushed, pushed, pushed.
Krish NAik: Because the index URL, I will test it.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is your build.
Krish NAik: Go to sleep.
Krish NAik: If you are in US region at East 2. It doesn't matter, you are anywhere, you can use East 1, otherwise, change…
Krish NAik: in your config. Wherever you have passed the region, in your GitHub secrets, in your deploy.yml, everywhere you need to, because your Lambda, S3, okay, these things needs to be exactly in the same region. If something is in the other region, it won't work.
Krish NAik: Alright, Rahul, that is fine.
Krish NAik: You started with that one. Directly, also, you can add it in requirement.txt. Like, before docklink, you can add that extra index. That only I will test it now.
Krish NAik: Once this deployment is done, then…
Krish NAik: Because now, the first time only, it should take…
Krish NAik: Not working in this layer exists. In the next time, most of the things will get catched, so the deployment will be fast.
Krish NAik: And even I have changed the build kit also, from QMA Engine 2, because QMA is really good for ARM64 images, not for x86 and 64 architecture-based images.
Krish NAik: Now, this image is close to 5GB.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I feel that sometimes
Krish NAik: the server connection is fast, and sometimes it's slow. Because of this 5GB upload, how to reduce that 5GB to a smaller version?
Krish NAik: Because I think in my ACR, plastic container.
Krish NAik: This is the one that takes SQL Server. Okay, so here will be coming. Now, the next idea, after the next one, my idea is to reduce that size, and that size will be reduced only with the help of Dockley.
Krish NAik: Yes, same issue, index strategy. Okay, I will do that, just wait.
Krish NAik: I will directly add it in requirements, rather than in docker.lambda. In that way, it becomes easier, okay? So, just wait, once this is done successfully, then I will come to that next one.
Krish NAik: Because right now, in your initial push, a lot of things get pushed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's meet.
Krish NAik: Because the next time, it will be a much faster build.
Krish NAik: Alright, now ECR is done. Okay, so let me just refresh this.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is 52675 GB. Okay, in the next one, with dockling optimized, we will check that, okay, remember.
Krish NAik: So, right now, updating the lambda function.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think, rest of the things are fine. Environment variables and other things that are being picked up from here.
Krish NAik: Updating the Lambda function takes around 60 seconds, so let's wait.
Krish NAik: Do I need that 3.12? Yes, 3.12 is the tag.
Krish NAik: Milith.
Krish NAik: It is mentioned in your deploy.vyman, so based on that tag, only the base image, will be created and uploaded in your base ECR.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Because, like last class, if you guys have really done it, same step, only I have taken that two-way Docker approach.
Krish NAik: No… I think the deployment is done. Okay, so what I will do, I will update my requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: Where is requirement.txt here?
Krish NAik: Okay, with this change, I will later push it, but…
Krish NAik: First of all, I think majorly, like, the lambda…
Krish NAik: update function should be done, okay? So, just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me go to my lambda… where is my lambda? Lambda.
Krish NAik: Just a simple word, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, updating the function, so once this becomes green, then we'll try to access it.
Krish NAik: extremely nice.
Krish NAik: Sorry.
Krish NAik: Alright, don't worry, I will look into that.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, fine. The lambda is updated.
Krish NAik: Configuration update will take place.
Krish NAik: Alright, you can see it here in the petty print.
Krish NAik: Okay, the application is up, let me open the spreader UI.
Krish NAik: Now what failed?
Krish NAik: Tls, this is fine. Deployment test failed already. Test has failed.
Krish NAik: But, just wait, let me see once here.
Krish NAik: Is the lambda function changing with respect to this one?
Krish NAik: Because during these deployments, Once I change something, something gets swapped.
Krish NAik: Where is my GitHub, GitHub? GitHub, yes.
Krish NAik: This is fine, the health point, okay, now this is the retrying logic, this is fine, there is no issue with that.
Krish NAik: Generally, it waited for the lambda…
Krish NAik: Okay, or the API gateway URL, that is fine, there is no issue in that.
Krish NAik: But, the function should be up.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can you see here?
Krish NAik: Okay, it took time. Generally, I've taken that 60 seconds. Because of that, it's telling failed, but I know it's working.
Krish NAik: So, now, with respect to get info, Let me try it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so majorly, this is fine with respect to the routes.
Krish NAik: A simple health check. Let me see if something is missing. Everything is true, true, true.
Krish NAik: Fine… I'll check info starts.
Krish NAik: Now, because I think already I will be having some vectors, let me try it out. Confirm true.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is my Pinecone index. Previously, there were 30 vectors, all were deleted. This route also I have checked.
Krish NAik: Then comes, let me try to upload a document.
Krish NAik: choose fail… I think the climate one is fine, let me see.
Krish NAik: If this is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me open my S3.
Krish NAik: In my S3, it's the docs Q&A.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once the route is successful, then I'll be showing you.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where the initialization of the PyTorch GPU takes a lot of time, that I feel.
Krish NAik: So let's wait.
Krish NAik: Generally, this should be somehow faster.
Krish NAik: Because in this route, a lot of things happens. First, it saves in local, it uploads to Pinecone. Okay, then it pushes to S3, so that's why this takes time.
Krish NAik: And let me check the logs also for my lambda.
Krish NAik: This route should not take so much time.
Krish NAik: I have EAR connected.
Krish NAik: Alright, Melind.
Krish NAik: EAR connected, what is EAR?
Krish NAik: I have here connected ER.
Krish NAik: created, like, created, you are telling. If you have created that.
Krish NAik: take my one, and then you can actually put… just be sure in your docker.lambda you have that base image ECRE URI with the tab should be correct.
Krish NAik: Let's look like some dockling, but again, let me see.
Krish NAik: Doppling, dropping… Gustel long… There is no text on all the events.
Krish NAik: Navy, like, it took a long time, but
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if I have deleted the Pinecone index, it came, but really, this took a long time.
Krish NAik: I was thinking that it was not working, but yes, it is working.
Krish NAik: Now… I'm feeling that, okay, if it is working.
Krish NAik: Let me check my S3 once.
Krish NAik: Hmm, S3?
Krish NAik: It should be available.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is a PDF that I have uploaded. For this PDF, this is the unique hash.
Krish NAik: In this unique hash, I have chunks.js1, document.pdf, and it's okay, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Now, let me quickly check, the…
Krish NAik: Okay, this is a list documents. Okay, so right now, it will show one document for sure, understanding the PDF one. Then comes query the document, let me pass it out.
Krish NAik: Let me pass the question. What are the impacts of climate change?
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, let me just do an execute here.
Krish NAik: Now, I will check the catcher part also, because the first time, it will take more response, close to around 15 to 20 seconds. Okay, so yes, now let me just do an execute. It should be much faster. Yes, the catcher part is working. This time, catch a hit is equal to true, alright.
Krish NAik: This got picked up. Okay, then comes… let's pass the unified query. Here, auto-approve SQL, make it true.
Krish NAik: Tell me the total number of customers in the database.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, this is also true, let me execute it.
Krish NAik: Let me see the SQL route.
Krish NAik: Customer count is 100, according to the database. Okay, this is also working fine. These are getting the catches stats.
Krish NAik: First of all, for your document level 1, docs catch a total document is 1,
Krish NAik: In that total objects that I have, 4. Okay. Clearing the cache, okay, this is fine. Clearing the vectors, it was working. Generate SQL is also working. Execute is also working.
Krish NAik: And pending, because I know, because otherwise there will be some issue with the hybrid road. So, purely, I can say that, yes, this entire thing is working.
Krish NAik: Okay? I have tested. Now, people are asking, if you are created, Poonam is asking, how git push to your branch will work for us.
Krish NAik: Poonam, you have to do a git pull. Okay, after that git pull, you have to push your own git push origin main.
Krish NAik: Why you will push to my branch? That is not possible.
Krish NAik: Okay, Balaji is telling, index URL alright fine, that index URL issue. So, this deployment is done successfully, okay? Now, I will do the Docker optimization here. So, I've added this requirement.txt right now for docklink, okay? So, let's see.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I think this is added.
Krish NAik: Dockling will update it, CPU, let me do now, new push. I will be doing the new push, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so requirement.txt, so this time I've updated it.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: This is the other way around. This line, I have not added it in docket.lambda. If you check my docket.lambda, okay, it's the old one only. Okay, but from there, it will be picked up. It's the same thing, just I have taken the alternate approach here.
Krish NAik: So, let me just make a commit.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just copy this stuff once, commit.
Krish NAik: Now, let me see if the deployment works on that. This is fine. Always remember, if, here, if the lambda function takes more than 60 seconds, okay, this will fail. Because I am not waiting for a long time, I will change… I can change that logic there in deploy.rymi. Okay, but, just be sure that, this part that
Krish NAik: You are checking directly with the function URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this part I have done now, I have started my new deployment. Let me, track the new deployment part.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, Melind, okay, in the meantime, just wait, Melind, then I will ask you to, whoever is getting the error, please, start sharing your screen.
Krish NAik: Balaji, just, I have added that particular line of extra index URL directly in the requirement.txt. I'm doing the testing. Till now, I've not done the testing, so just wait. Once the testing is done, then I will come to that part.
Krish NAik: So guys, just wait. Because the original dock link is working fine, but the idea is to reduce the Docker size from 5GB to at least 2GB, 3GB, whatever.
Krish NAik: So, just wait, everyone.
Krish NAik: Because my base image is already built, so I'm not worried about that. The Docker build should be faster this time.
Krish NAik: I can see so many unwanted things are here.
Krish NAik: Okay, rack texture, SQL, Linux platform, okay, fine. Git commit, Docker is ready, AWS credentials verified.
Krish NAik: Login to ECR is done, log in, verify ECR login is done, check and build image if needed. Base image is already there, directly started working on the application part, okay? Now here, let me see if the docklink is working or not.
Krish NAik: If here also it fails, it means that some issue is there.
Krish NAik: The CPU build-up docklink is actually creating the issue.
Krish NAik: Because that is a solution in local, it's working, but in the deployment with respect to
Krish NAik: I did not, complete.
Krish NAik: Mmm… alright, fine, this is the one.
Krish NAik: Error with respect to your PIP install, this one that I am getting, okay? This is fine.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Okay, now the optimization, because…
Krish NAik: This is what needs to be done. Hint.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: See, ubpip install hyphen r requirement.txt target, not complete.
Krish NAik: The target is the actual place and here.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm telling request package was not found, or request was… I'm feeling at, but not at the requested version.
Krish NAik: Index, by default, we will only consider versions, okay, just wait. Let me see, like, what the hello is coming for this one.
Krish NAik: Let me see the server once.
Krish NAik: Alright, it's telling to add that, find link approach.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me try the find link approach, which is suggested.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this is with respect to UV as I am working with, okay? Just wait.
Krish NAik: This is suggested… Okay, so let me see.
Krish NAik: get status, because the ID, I don't know why it's low.
Krish NAik: requirement.txt… Get status, update REQ.
Krish NAik: just with, I'm pushing a… But, manually from the command line.
Krish NAik: Okay, again, I pushed it.
Krish NAik: Because it will be faster, so I can do multiple testing now.
Krish NAik: Previously, this testing used to actually take a lot of time because of the base image part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait.
Krish NAik: Once my part is done, then only do it, guys. Right now, you guys don't do anything, just wait for my bill to be successful.
Krish NAik: Because if I… if I will not work with UV, then it will work fine, but I am as working with UV, that's why.
Krish NAik: And this is one of those. The other one that I will try is index strategy on Save Base Match.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because somebody told me in the chat, I think, who was that?
Krish NAik: Rahul or someone told me.
Krish NAik: I don't remember, but let's see that whether this works or not.
Krish NAik: Now, let's see whether it fails or not.
Krish NAik: Dockling fail, where we get there right now?
Krish NAik: But tell now, it's picking up the NVIDIA packages, that's… All right.
Krish NAik: Because I know this will work, then, because it looks like it's falling back to the GPU-based one.
Krish NAik: leave this part, and let's get back.
Krish NAik: Because the optimization that we are doing, it has fallback to the condition.
Krish NAik: Just let me see once…
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: This is the Docker one.
Krish NAik: Talency here, embedded, docklink, great quality, but painfully slow.
Krish NAik: It's a valid one.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is the main Docker one. Okay, this is the Docker UV images.
Krish NAik: Dockling API, Docker confus… Mmm… image CPU one.
Krish NAik: Because your media structure, So, do I have, token?
Krish NAik: This is the Granite Dockling.
Krish NAik: Granite dockling is for, VLLM, I don't need this.
Krish NAik: This is the VLLM integration.
Krish NAik: Let me search only for top cling images, then I can actually take the base image.
Krish NAik: So, on top of this, another base 2 strategy.
Krish NAik: Somebody has done, but again, 6 months ago, brain part.
Krish NAik: from IBM, there is no official Dockling one. This is from IBM, but again, this is Granite Dockling.
Krish NAik: Granite Dockling, I don't need. In multimodal rack, probably I'll be using granite Dockling, but not for now.
Krish NAik: Mmm, alright.
Krish NAik: Extended URL also field.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me add this at the end.
Krish NAik: This is the other strategy which is suggested.
Krish NAik: Alright, index strategy on set best match.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait, keep going.
Krish NAik: Let's find taxi worker.
Krish NAik: Because FineLinks is not working, okay?
Krish NAik: Again, I have to do a get status just to it.
Krish NAik: It's status… New requirement is updated, and this also updated, so docker.lambda.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's see now.
Krish NAik: I've done a few changes.
Krish NAik: Because this build will work fine, okay, there is no issue.
Krish NAik: But again, like, I pushed the new one.
Krish NAik: Because those deployments really, like, when you are actually working with deployments.
Krish NAik: Going forward, I'm planning to keep a Docker image in my own Docker hub.
Krish NAik: For Dockling very specifically, because for your multimodal rag also, I'll be using Dockling a lot.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, because the core docklink part, everybody should test it, it should work, given I have tested it and shown you.
Krish NAik: But the CPU Docklink build, if it is… it should work, actually.
Krish NAik: Because that is much lighter, according to the official docklink documentation.
Krish NAik: Because Linux CPU-only version, this is only exactly that I need.
Krish NAik: Let me see now whether I get an error here or not.
Krish NAik: Somehow, the packages has reduced from 277 to 256.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, this strategy worked.
Krish NAik: Let's see now the size in ECR.
Krish NAik: Okay, 5267 is the existing one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now let's see, like, what is the new size.
Krish NAik: Because I feel at least it should be 1 or 2GB less. The NVIDIA libraries takes a lot of space.
Krish NAik: Alright, Rahul is telling, RAG Text2SQL… RAG Text2SQL Server, I have still… I'm encountering issues like name unknown, the repository with the name RAG Text2SQL does not exist.
Krish NAik: Alright, just wait. We'll come to that.
Krish NAik: Because exporting layer, let's see, like, what is the new size.
Krish NAik: If this is done, then… Great.
Krish NAik: Because, what is the other way around approach? Okay, if you want to do it, I'm telling, like, if this approach will also fail in my case.
Krish NAik: Okay, it worked actually, but if it failed, then manually, I would have written in my docker.lambda, here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I would have written very specifically, this thing. Like, uvpape install requirement, I will remove docklink from requirement.txt and add that, like, uvpape install docklink that entire link.
Krish NAik: That is the manual way around. But I didn't take that manual way around, though this approach worked, it looks like.
Krish NAik: Srinivas, you just take a clone of the recent one that I have done, because now I've not tested one, but let me do the testing, then you can take the recent, clone if you want to do, or the same repo if you want to do a git pull.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait.
Krish NAik: Alright, the push is taking place.
Krish NAik: Now I got a mill, the run failed.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Now, all images are pushed to ECR. Let me check now.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's see what is the expected size.
Krish NAik: Can you see the difference in size, guys?
Krish NAik: Everybody.
Krish NAik: Like, why I was working on that CPU build, very specifically, why?
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: The size of the image now, and size of the image before.
Krish NAik: Okay, like… the redemption is… quite low, I can say.
Krish NAik: 30-70%, but let's say the application works or not. That is the final goal. Okay, because this is the level of optimization, because I know, like, your NVIDIA libraries takes a lot of space. Okay, so I don't need them, so let's see now this particular build is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: The first, success criteria, this optimization is done. Okay, now let's look for the final one.
Krish NAik: Okay, updating the lambda function again, it will take some time.
Krish NAik: Okay, it looks like updating… okay, now this will take, okay, because this is a test deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, even if this fails, doesn't matter, so I will just… fine, okay. I will update this script, and I will remove the API gateway part here.
Krish NAik: Let me just check and get to my… This one.
Krish NAik: Where is my Texas SQL?
Krish NAik: Looks like the function is working fine. Let me try to do a reload.
Krish NAik: Okay, of this page, the container will start. It will take 10 seconds to 15 seconds.
Krish NAik: All right, Sydney was fine.
Krish NAik: Function in the back time, it's getting updated, it looks like.
Krish NAik: Two things happen, simply error if we get, then we can understand some issue is there.
Krish NAik: If… The updating the lambda function, it's taking time.
Krish NAik: Alright, if I do a reload, yes, everything is working fine. Now let me pass slash talks… Yeah, okay.
Krish NAik: So, first of all… reset, okay?
Krish NAik: Because I think the initial, part with respect to S3
Krish NAik: Initialization, try it out, default, make it true. I will just delete it, my existing vectors, 25, it's fine. Let me try to upload a document.
Krish NAik: try it out, choose file. Okay, let me check with the JSON file.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, JSON hit, false.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, if I try to execute the same stuff again, the catch-it condition is true.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, yes. If this is working fine, this is the only route where docklink matters.
Krish NAik: Other than that, in the rest of the places, if I ask any questions with respect to, for example, documents.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, for example here, this will be picked up from the… Json file.
Krish NAik: What are the impacts of climate change?
Krish NAik: Okay, so this will come from the JSON.
Krish NAik: Alright, ewe.json, the file name, fine. Okay, so this is faster. PDF processing is somehow I feel that.
Krish NAik: Okay, just… I know the existing routes will work, okay? So, guys, all level of optimization, we have done it, and the application is working, because this was the only routes upload which is related to dockly. Other routes are not related to dockly. So, yes, it works fine.
Krish NAik: Now, I think I'm good to go with our patients and people who are facing issues.
Krish NAik: Alright, so guys, okay, so one by one, people who are having the issues, please raise your hand. I'll be taking the push, one by one.
Krish NAik: Murta, what is the… check my last comment.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rahul, I will, mute. Just, I'm showing you the commit exactly, okay? Rahul, in the meantime, you can go ahead, where is GitHub? This is my GitHub summary, okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here,
Krish NAik: I think this is update requirements new, this is the one. So here, what I have done, see, I have added this one at the last of docket.lambda, only this one, index strategy and say, best match.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is one change.
Krish NAik: Rest, everything is fine. And then, in requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: I have added this extra index URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mothraza, check the latest commit. Only two things are there.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, Ram.
Rahul Parihar: So… Paul, let me share my screen. I don't know what's happening, but I made,
Rahul Parihar: a major change.
Rahul Parihar: to try to understand what changed.
Rahul Parihar: Can you give me, permission to share?
Krish NAik: Let me add you to panelists. Others also, please let me know. Only Raul has raised here. What about others?
Krish NAik: Yes, you can take the latest pull, take the latest one, get pulled, okay, everybody. Abhishek says NVIDIA mail dependencies are removed, then the document processing will take the… he… see, actually, Abhishek, NVIDIA GPU is not available in my Lambda environment, so it really doesn't matter whether I'm doing the installation.
Krish NAik: it becomes, like, useless, because I don't have the hardware to do the executions of that.
Krish NAik: And really, you can understand the size. From 5GB, it got to 1.3 GB. Close to 4GB, we have reduced, so that is really good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Alright, Raul, now I'm looking into your screen.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: Brothers, also, please do that.
Rahul Parihar: I haven't.
Krish NAik: Let me…
Rahul Parihar: I have made the changes, but I wanted to understand what's… why it is happening that way.
Rahul Parihar: one… The image was getting built successfully over here.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Rahul Parihar: But it was not getting pushed, so something… something was going wrong with the…
Rahul Parihar: pushing of the image, you know? Like, yeah, it's a verbose… just trying to debug this thing, because best way is to learn through debug.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: So here, you see the image is getting built.
Rahul Parihar: And, but…
Krish NAik: Okay, I agree.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, when… because we are giving a repository image as Image them as… this is…
Krish NAik: This is a bee's image. This is a bee image.
Rahul Parihar: It's a base image, yeah, yeah.
Krish NAik: This image, in your case, it's working fine. This is fine. Now, this is the push, I think, to your, main application image, which is that RAT text to SQL, so I think… show your ACR once.
Rahul Parihar: So what… yeah, so what I ask the code, and the code says that,
Rahul Parihar: basically, we were missing, to create an ECR repository if it exists or doesn't exist, you know?
Krish NAik: I think the ECA repository is just like the same last class only, no?
Krish NAik: See, here, if I see ECR repo is rack texture SQL, lambda function name is Serverless. Okay, this is fine, and, generally, like, just because…
Rahul Parihar: Your login is successful.
Krish NAik: Yeah. Go back to easier and show me that home.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I have now, what I did.
Krish NAik: I rebuilt.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I just, I just pushed…
Krish NAik: that auto… okay, actually, I think, yeah, if ECR is available, so let's…
Rahul Parihar: So it's pushing now, okay.
Krish NAik: Layer already exists, alright?
Krish NAik: Updating the lambda fine.
Krish NAik: Because if ECR is already available, that's why I told you, you know, those two ECR. We can create the ECR through deploy. This one.
Rahul Parihar: Yes, we have to add this code, right? Like, in the…
Krish NAik: Not necessary. In my case, it's not there, because only the existence of the ECR matters.
Krish NAik: If the ECR is already there, then you don't need to create it again. Then why you'll be creating?
Rahul Parihar: deleted the ECR image, right?
Rahul Parihar: Because we are moving everything in the Lambda family.
Krish NAik: The R is different, EMH is different. DMH lies within your ECR.
Krish NAik: the repository.
Krish NAik: I only deleted the image.
Rahul Parihar: Oh.
Krish NAik: I never deleted the ECR repo.
Krish NAik: Okay, you deleted the ECR repo also.
Rahul Parihar: I deleted the ECR report also.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay. Actually, see, I only deleted the image every time when I do it.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, okay, okay, got it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: I deleted the ECR repo also, that's… okay, that's the reason why, okay.
Rahul Parihar: Got it.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, thanks. I should check.
Krish NAik: Because if you add that script, no, what will happen, see, if the existing repo exists with the same name, on top of that, again, if you try to do it, it becomes a problem. So, rather than only creating in your deploy.yml, keep a logic.
Krish NAik: If this repo exists, okay, then it's fine. If it does not exist, then only create it. That condition, keep it in your deploy. That is must include there.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, one change that I did, and from your thing, I did not update the Docklin thing, I just…
Rahul Parihar: I just did the change, in the Docker image, that index change that I was telling, right? The index strategy, unsafe, best match. Even then, that the image that I'm now seeing, I've not done the remaining changes, but the image size that I'm seeing is, is 13, 1.3.
Rahul Parihar: you know.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, they're the same size that we saw, no? 1.5.
Rahul Parihar: Either way, you can do that change, right? Either in the docker… dockerfile.lambda, or…
Krish NAik: Yes, you can pass it directly in dockerfile.lambda or in the requirement.txt, in both the ways, it's fine.
Rahul Parihar: I'll sign off, thanks.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Next, Balaji, others also, raise your hand. Balaji test deployment step is failing. Whoever is failing, raise your hand, guys. Because in this case, I need to really see your screen.
Balaji Rengan: Can I share my screen?
Krish NAik: Yes, Baraji, just wait, I will add you to the panelist.
Krish NAik: Okay, hmm…
Krish NAik: others. I think in the last class, ECR, ES, that is the main idea. It's like, once you create the repo, you really don't need to delete it. Only delete the base images.
Balaji Rengan: It's been screened, Paul.
Krish NAik: Okay, now here, verify the API Gateway URL. Oh, no, no, this is fine. Check directly in Lambda, because, see, I removed that functionality of API Gateway, the script I will update, but open your function URL. This is fine, this is fine, this is not to worry about.
Balaji Rengan: Fine. Okay, thank you, yeah.
Krish NAik: No, no, check, check, show me that the function URL is working on me.
Balaji Rengan: Okay, okay, yeah.
Krish NAik: Check the function URL part.
Balaji Rengan: So, you, you meant that.
Krish NAik: Open your Lambda page. Lambda page?
Balaji Rengan: Lambda… oh, okay, sorry.
Krish NAik: use. From here, open lambda.
Krish NAik: Go to your function, the function URL that got generated, click on that, and see the application.
Balaji Rengan: Custom, it takes some time, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, first time, like, 15 to 20 seconds it will take. Others, please raise your hands. Saurabh is there. Okay, yes, Saurabh.
Krish NAik: no audio from Sora of others. In chat, let me know.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah. So, I have a very basic question, so I thought to towards the end, but let me, share my screen.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will add you.
Balaji Rengan: Two panelists.
Krish NAik: What happened, Balaji? You can start sharing, just wait, no, I think the app should work.
Balaji Rengan: Okay, good.
Balaji Rengan: Yeah, my mind is going on, okay, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, going on, Mr. I think that,
Krish NAik: cold start is taking place. Poonam is asking, I missed last two classes, Lambda we created. See, in the last session we ever attended, that Sunday class was important, because a lot of debugging and other students that we did.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, if you miss two classes, I think the deployment started from last two classes.
Krish NAik: And the deployment is not very hard, but little complex. Like, if you're a direct beginner, it can be a problem.
Krish NAik: So, like…
Balaji Rengan: All it has come, so I got the response.
Krish NAik: You got the response, no? Alright, do a testing, and then let me know.
Balaji Rengan: Yeah, also, thanks, yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, Poonam, just, go through, like, today's session, if you follow, really, the last session, a lot of things, so, like, just be sure you are using the same region. If you are changing the region, be sure you are updating it in deploy.yml. So, all those things, just take care of that, Poonam.
saurabh verma: Yeah. So, I'm sharing my screen. My question is very basic.
Krish NAik: Yes.
saurabh verma: Actually, I was also an official travel, so could not attend the last two classes, but my question is very basic. So, I have taken the latest poll.
saurabh verma: Okay? Now…
Krish NAik: Right?
saurabh verma: And now, if I want to push to my… and this is mapped to, my, GitHub repository, okay, over here.
saurabh verma: Which is, I have taken a fork from yours, okay? So, if I have to push, then, can I push to my, repository, as well as have the, connect with your Git also?
Krish NAik: He's here.
saurabh verma: Possible.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, you can do it, no? First of all, open that, and just be sure you are in sync with my latest.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I did that.
Krish NAik: If you have done the same, do any small change. Just, do a small change, something, okay, and then try to push it.
saurabh verma: So, a good status?
Krish NAik: Quite good status.
Krish NAik: Because now I think you have not done any major change.
saurabh verma: No, I've not done any major change.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think… but your git status is telling modified.env.example again.
saurabh verma: Oh, that…
Krish NAik: standard.
saurabh verma: That I was… that I modified when you were explaining, so I had modified it.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay.
saurabh verma: Yeah, it is there.
Krish NAik: Probably fine.
Krish NAik: Like, you can do any small change, okay, and just be sure those files are related to your kit. Like, if you do any change in .envy, those things doesn't matter.
Krish NAik: it is, involved in .gitignore file. So, any major file, just do a small event space change, then do a git status, git add dot, whatever that file that you have, and then you can do a git push origin.
Krish NAik: So that people…
saurabh verma: So that'll go to my repository, and it will work.
Krish NAik: Yes.
saurabh verma: Okay.
Krish NAik: And before that just we show the GitHub secrets you have configured.
saurabh verma: Right, right. And, the two things I would like to discuss at the end, I have done one small project, where I've used semantic search and explainability, and using RAG also, so I would like to show that to you, but towards the end, you can take the questions of others. I'll remain muted.
Krish NAik: Alright, you can share me the Republic. I can take the questions, and I can take it.
saurabh verma: Okay.
Krish NAik: I'll repeat that thing in the chat. Yes, Anirud and…
saurabh verma: One last thing, sorry, one last thing. There is a India AI Impact, event, which is happening big in, Delhi, from February 16th to 20th.
Krish NAik: Yes, gelison is coming, I know.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah. So, we are into AI, and we are participating, and one of the concepts that we are launching is about R&D Lab, because we are doing a lot of R&D and developing products on AI.
saurabh verma: But, I wanted to explore, like, having a MOU and a collaboration with you, or Crichai Technologies, where…
Krish NAik: Kish will go to the event, okay? During that time, message me. Koresh, and I have told the marketing guy, because for me, really, because again, I have to travel, that's why I think. He'll be leaving on 15th of Feb, that's planned. Yesterday, I had a discussion with him. He's also going, because he will be taking the interview of a few people, that's why.
saurabh verma: Okay, so how do I contact him? Through your marketing WhatsApp group?
Krish NAik: First message me, then I will…
saurabh verma: I don't… I don't have your phone number.
Krish NAik: Don't worry, you drop me a mail, APP at directional.
saurabh verma: Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: In our sleep.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Hi, sir, this is Aniroth. Shall I ask my question, sir?
Krish NAik: Yes, do you want to share your screen?
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: No, sir, so it's just a question. So, in our…
Krish NAik: Do you want to just wait? Abhishek has also raised. Abhishek, do you want to share?
Abhishek: No, also, I have some questions.
Krish NAik: Millions?
Krish NAik: Okay, just people you want to share, let me just add them first. Milind, do you want to share?
milind kulkarni: Yes. Can you hear me?
Krish NAik: Yes, I can, okay. In the meantime, I'm adding you to panelists, Aniroth first, Yugo, then Abhishe Yogu.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: So, in our company, let's say, so we are planning to build, an agent kind of, system like Azure or a cloud.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: So, the basic idea is, when we give the access to a particular code base and give the requirement, it should be able to create the code and then do all the things, in line. So, my question was, which… how… what's the checking strategy that has to be used? Because we are completely using the, code, as a, source, right? So, what should be a checking strategy, and how to
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Go ahead, any headset on that one session?
Krish NAik: There is not much… their rag doesn't come into the picture so much.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, if you're building something like…
Krish NAik: Like, what is, like, if you have your own codebase, why want to do the chunking on top of your own codebase?
Krish NAik: That's the main thing. See, like, the entire, like…
Krish NAik: I can say that, for example, if you have 2,000 fines.
Krish NAik: Okay, rather than you can keep some information, it means that this file, this is the structure, this is the function, keep some pseudocode. Every line of code, if you want to keep it, because the idea is that it should go to DAT, and from there, it should fetch it.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Okay. Because if you have really one class, just think about 1300 lives.
Krish NAik: for everything, such a big function, even keep it. Because here, chunking doesn't matter, really. You have to maintain,
Krish NAik: The function logic, the class level logic, those things we have to maintain.
Krish NAik: So here, chart can really… doesn't… because it's much more from coding side. So here, generally in these type of problems, you go ahead with bigger chunks. Murthas are the rest, Murthasa, if you want to add any…
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Yeah, my second question is, so this is basically based on agent kind of an architecture. So, which framework would be better to use here and,
Krish NAik: Langrav, start with Langrav. Langrav will give you much more control.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Oh, that is the best, I feel. Like, could you AI and Agro is easier to start with.
Krish NAik: they have certain code executors also within them, you can check that. But, like, I feel better with respect to, I can say. Now, always remember, whenever you are doing your code basis, okay, so generally, another thing, you should have very good documentation.
Krish NAik: Markdown phrase.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Like, doc strings matter.
Krish NAik: If you have a function without a donk string, that plays a very crucial… it means both the things, like, in our product, in ZenoDocs also, we have seen that.
Krish NAik: Okay, every function, every class, they should have very good drop strings, because those drop strings play a very crucial role for the LL.
Krish NAik: Whenever, like, if you are going ahead with any type of chunk or any mechanism, it actually helps you. So, you should have very, very good quality talk strings, documentations are required. In some cases, even I don't parse .py files also.
Krish NAik: I just take the project structure mainly, and probably the things which are required much more documentation, then if you have examples that, also plays, but I think in your case, examples are not required.
Krish NAik: Because generally, for a library, whenever we look into a library, we look into the examples folder. There, from there, we understand that, okay, these are the different type of implementations.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: So, any idea on what framework or how this cursor and Cloth Code are using? So, because their agent seems to be very fast.
Krish NAik: First of all, like, you need to define an architecture, let me see…
Krish NAik: Let me give you a sample reference, okay, just wait. I have to open my…
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: So, in the last class, you were referring to one of the projects that might take 3-4 months, you were telling. So, this was similar to what I'm talking about, right, so that you had planned.
Krish NAik: Just wait, just wait once.
Krish NAik: Because, again, that repo, some repo, I forget, and that's why I just request.
Krish NAik: I will share you at least your startup, where you can start your work. Generally, for this, you need,
Krish NAik: It's not only agent, you need AgentFS, Agent File System.
milind kulkarni: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that, like, commands like ls, grep.
Krish NAik: which are very… WC3, those are very, very important, okay? So, just wait, if I get that…
Krish NAik: Because I think, Lord put 10 plates.
Krish NAik: Two to three months back, I was actually working on such a use case.
Krish NAik: Hmm… district.
Krish NAik: Superpower, automator, returns, just return…
Krish NAik: Mmm, this is also my Dixel ginger.
Krish NAik: Yeah, 170 architectures, moon… Mmm, will be at context engineering…
Krish NAik: Even where I kept that link up.
Krish NAik: Let's make it…
Krish NAik: Joe Sweet.
Krish NAik: No, this is the full report.
Krish NAik: Bye.
Krish NAik: Okay, good time.
Krish NAik: Was that link, even I forgot.
Krish NAik: Where is that?
Krish NAik: I'm currently given I have posted.
Krish NAik: Let…
Krish NAik: Hmm… bankruptcy assistant.
Krish NAik: I actually forget where I pasted it at, but later on, let me…
Krish NAik: Per chip, because there, it was that architecture. You have to build an architecture, for example, like, you can take a reference like Claude Hood or anything.
Krish NAik: Because later on, like, those things are extension, like cursor and other things. First of all, do it in the level of.
Krish NAik: command line interface, CLI.
Krish NAik: Then you can create a… Extension in VS Code or anything.
Krish NAik: Or something like that.
Krish NAik: So, like, in command… like, in agent FS level, it means that, first of all, you have to decide your… I mean, like, your orchestration, your master agent, that master should have control for how many agents, then those will do, like, what type of task.
Krish NAik: web search… okay, in that we have to define and complete architecture. That particular document I had, but 2 months back, I was exploring that one.
Krish NAik: Once I get that, then, tomorrow let me see. Just give me a reminder.
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Sure, sir, sure. Thank you, sir.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so we had that, but now I'm not…
Krish NAik: Paper then code, nice and… Okay, I think next I can take it out.
Abhishek: Hey, hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: I will do that, don't worry. Because even, like, I was working two months back on that, so in that architecture.
Krish NAik: Yes. People who want to share their screen, they can start sharing. In the meantime, Asma…
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: What's.
Krish NAik: What I'm…
Anirudh pavan prasad cg: Meanwhile, if you get the link today in the class, so can you please paste it in the community as well, session? Because if people leave the class, they will not get access to the.
Krish NAik: Alright, alright. Because that is a Stanford guy, he did his own research.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is… that was much better than… That one, and… Based on his metrics, actually…
Krish NAik: Okay, got it.
Krish NAik: Okay, actually, I checked it till September. I was thinking November.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, coordinates intelligent contextual.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is always a start point. Okay, I'm sharing this…
Krish NAik: Great, okay. Now, this is a work from where you can take the reference.
Krish NAik: Let me just look…
Krish NAik: Desktop… this is desktops too… I think, yes, multi-agent coding system. Can you see this one? Okay.
Krish NAik: No, this report was actually good.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in the Stanford groups, it was going around, so… So, this is, like, a multi-agent restarting. Like, Stanford has a terminal bench. Whenever you are building any coding agent, this is the benchmark that you need to follow.
Krish NAik: Okay, the terminal benchmark. I'm sharing this in the chat, but you can look. This is an older implementation, I was working a little, but right now I'm not working in this one.
Krish NAik: But, there are much better updates, so you can actually look into. So, this actually was better than CloudTrak during that time he built it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, actually, I looked into this implementation. It's based purely on Python. So you can actually go, and from there, at least you can take what are the different type of agents.
Krish NAik: state, orchestra, sub-agents, okay, and whenever you are building something, do a benchmark on terminal range. That is a major one for all coding systems uses that.
Krish NAik: Alright, right now I will look into other accounts.
Krish NAik: Okay, well, I'm looking into Milan's screen. In the meantime, like, others, Asma, Poonam, Appreciate it, yes, more time.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, yeah, Paul, thanks, Paul. I just have, one question. So…
Murtuza Saifee: Actually, I'm doing some, you know, building some of the experiments around those, different, different
Murtuza Saifee: rack processes, because I want to evaluate some of the things in the organization. So, one of the things that I was checking is the set.
Poonam Nanda: Charles Mirana?
Krish NAik: Please be on mute, who will be mute.
Poonam Nanda: They include…
Krish NAik: Yes. Notice.
Murtuza Saifee: So, one of the things which, I was checking was self-rag. So, is that SRAG?
Krish NAik: That only, tomorrow I will be talking about it. SRAG helps you much more from that LLM content quality. Whereas CRAG is on the retrieval quality. That's why, two levels. That's why I've taken the web app also that I have built, it's… both the rags are there. Then, finally, like, you have the adaptive one.
Krish NAik: Okay. Then, like, that's a combination of C and S, that's referred to as adaptive, with a little bit of changes. We'll go through the paper also.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, yeah, because that's what I was thinking, like, we already discussed the… because I checked, a few of the, you know, like, benchmarkings, a few of the blogs, and SelfRag has, a good precision and recall as well, so, like.
Murtuza Saifee: Every time.
Krish NAik: CRAG is better. For recall, like, corrective rag is much better. Like, cell prep paper is a bit older, CRAG is a little bit newer, but both have different cases, one for the recurable quality.
Krish NAik: Making it better than other the LLM generation quality, so that's really… we'll be talking about that tomorrow.
Murtuza Saifee: Alright, alright, thanks. Thank you.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
milind kulkarni: So, Paul, can you see my screen?
Krish NAik: Yes, I can see.
Krish NAik: Only…
milind kulkarni: I had a small question about… now I got that ECR fixed, so it is building. I wanted to see where you can see that it is using cache or not.
Krish NAik: Tash, again, I hate to know. Ask something. Have you uploaded any PDF? It means that some.
milind kulkarni: Yeah, there is already PDF there. There is, there is already…
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, just ask a query, ask a query.
Krish NAik: Simply ask a query.
Krish NAik: Okay, now CCC, who are the authors? You got some result. Now click execute, you will get the result faster.
Krish NAik: When you executed this query, if the query will be the same, you will be… like, it should be working.
milind kulkarni: Maybe 10-15 minutes back.
Krish NAik: Just go below.
Krish NAik: You will see catch a hit is equal to true, okay, but your catch rate actually took so much time. Generally, when it's, catch8 is true, I know. Okay, but, try to click again, because you get faster responses. I don't know why it took me.
milind kulkarni: No, now it is faster. No, because this was, like, probably…
milind kulkarni: 5-10 minutes back. Okay, no worries.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
milind kulkarni: Great, thank you.
milind kulkarni: Thanks, I'll stop sharing.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, next, I think, Asma Poonam.
Krish NAik: Vishayk, anyone can go ahead.
Asma Sultana: Hi, Paul. How do I share? I don't… I don't see the permission here.
Krish NAik: Wait, wait, wait, wait, I will add in.
Krish NAik: Abhishek and Poonam, you guys can let me know.
Poonam Nanda: So, for me, for me, Sugan, so basically, I have not created the lambdas, obviously it will not work, and I guess there are other things also that I have missed. But when I pushed to my Git, the action did not start. So, is there anything that I need to do it before today's class, or it should have been started?
Poonam Nanda: I can see my code there, but action is not starting.
Krish NAik: Alright, alright, alright. See, Poonam, in your case, refer the file. This is the actual, in the last class, I told everyone to follow this file. NewDeploy.md. Under your tops, you'll be having this new deploy.empt.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, step by step, things are written. Because in my case, my expectation is that you have both the ECR repos, you should have the Lambda, you should have the access policy, all those things configured, and then you start the deployment. So here.
Poonam Nanda: Yeah, so maybe I'll go through that, and then we'll.
Krish NAik: Yes, that's why in last Saturday, I think this I discussed.
Poonam Nanda: I'll check this new deploy.md, and then I'll go through this one.
Krish NAik: Location.
Poonam Nanda: Thank you.
Abhishek: Paul, so, just a question, like, you know, we have used Magnum, for, .
Krish NAik: Sometimes I say manganom, it's wrong, it's actually manum.
Abhishek: Okay, fine. So, so why, why, why not API Gateway, and why am I going?
Krish NAik: No, no, see, API Gateway is a different service, but, generally what happens, like, there is a hard limit of 29 seconds, no.
Abhishek: In API Gateway. In my case, if I have a bigger PDF, if DocL takes 1 minute or 2 minutes, simply it will say, time out.
Abhishek: Okay, but then we can use, for this hard, 29 second, right, we can use WebSocket as well, right?
Krish NAik: WebSocket, you can use it. There is no issue in that. WebSocket, you can use it, really, but generally, it depends, like, when you want to use WebSockets.
Abhishek: Hmm.
Krish NAik: just for file uploading and others, I don't feel like… generally, if I'm building a scalable chat system, then I will prefer WebSockets. So, it depends on that.
Abhishek: So now, yeah, I mean, again, my question is on scaling, right? So, with reducing API Gateway, we can scale easily and, you know, or Lambda also scales, right?
Krish NAik: See, the main problem with API Gateway, then you can say in the API Gateway, okay, like, once you upload the document, you can say that it is in queue.
Krish NAik: Okay, and done. It means that you won't be showing you the response at total chance and other things. Later on, behind the scenes, it's actually going on.
Krish NAik: You have to understand that. So, because that 29 heart limit is there, just because of that.
Abhishek: So, so, like, when we, when we go to the scaling part, right, let's suppose we have multiple users coming around, let's suppose 100 users, so how this scaling will be, handled, with this ECR, like, these images will be replicated, what, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Right now, I've not done any scaling. Later on, if I switch it to ECS with Farricate, I can do that.
Krish NAik: automatic, if it's required, the images will come into the picture. Okay, so right now, I've not used ECS with Fargate. I think, for your third project, or for your fourth project, I'll be using that.
Abhishek: Okay, fair, full. Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Automatically, but again, always remember it's, costly.
Krish NAik: That's why. Generally, for 100 users, okay, ECS is fine, but just remember, like, if you are hitting, like, 1 lakh requests per second, then ECS is not, then Kubernetes is better.
Krish NAik: Okay, ECS, fine, 1,000, 2,000 ECS, but again, I feel that it's a costlier solution. Okay, it's good to actually use in production, everybody uses it. Okay, so that's why I'll be showing you that in one of the projects. ECS will part of it.
Abhishek: Got it. Okay, yeah, thank you. That's all.
Krish NAik: Yes, anybody else?
Krish NAik: Who want to ask any question?
Krish NAik: Okay, no more questions. Okay, start up.
Krish NAik: The work that you have done, I think you were telling…
Krish NAik: Paul Asma, I cannot hear you. I can see your mic, Jason, but I cannot hear you, Asma.
Krish NAik: Pradhan is asking, what do you think about the Anthropic AI recent, plugin, which may…
Krish NAik: Yes, actually, see, previously, like, plugins, they have kept it.
Krish NAik: But on the alternate of other developers who are using MCP servers, plugin makes your life much easier. It's really…
Krish NAik: Good, I will say. For development, it makes much more easier for anyone, so that's why now everybody will be launching their plugins, and even they have a dedicated marketplace.
Krish NAik: Okay, from that marketplace, like, anybody can bring any third-party things and easier integration. So, that development is much easier right now. People will be focusing much more on architecting stuff.
Krish NAik: Much more on system design.
Krish NAik: That's why billions of dollars, even the… I think, there,
Krish NAik: both the markets were down. Dow Jones was also down.
Krish NAik: And this is also done.
Krish NAik: Indian stock markets are also hit because of that.
Krish NAik: Even the crypto market is also down, everything is down now.
Krish NAik: over 6-2 months, almost, 1,000 codes will be written by EI. Yes, I can say 100% of…
Krish NAik: Because it's much more about designing, but again, like, once AI writes your quota, validation and other things.
Krish NAik: schema framework, pseudocode, all those things needs to be decided by you, Prada.
Krish NAik: Once you have done the entire plan, then you give it to the AI. And just be sure if AI is sticking to the rule.
Krish NAik: That is also important.
Krish NAik: Lambda tips and image tags. Asma, I cannot hear you, just try to change your mic and test it.
Krish NAik: I am having the following issue, load metadata.
Krish NAik: Unexpected 401 unauthorized, expected status.
Krish NAik: HTTP is… Lambda divs.
Krish NAik: HTTPL load metadata from… Okay, I need to see your screen, Asma, and just…
Krish NAik: Be on the mic, because it's harder to understand through chats.
Krish NAik: You are in panelists, you can share your screen.
milind kulkarni: Metal detectors and video surveillance.
Asma Sultana: are implemented to help make sure no…
milind kulkarni: We use a data center core without authorization.
milind kulkarni: When a hard drive is retired.
Krish NAik: people who will be going to the Delhi summit, just be sure, like, contact me. Then, like, I'll be sharing,
Krish NAik: Or something like that, Kreish contact, whoever is going there. Because I think Darius will be going.
Krish NAik: Because Krisht asked me again, because I have the batches on Wednesday, that's why it becomes harder for me, okay? So, if you want to meet Krish, I will tell you. I'm sure, alright, I'm sure, okay. You guys can let me know tomorrow, then, based on that.
milind kulkarni: services that want to make themselves available on the internet register themselves.
Krish NAik: My email ID, APP at the rate, kreshnag.in, app.
milind kulkarni: CFD checks incoming network.
Krish NAik: Here, this is fine. You're in B… this is… argument, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Show me the terror apartments.
milind kulkarni: your scale of this?
Krish NAik: Where you check their… that push again.
milind kulkarni: Find a chair.
Krish NAik: Here it's telling load metadata, from Lambda, load metadata grow.
milind kulkarni: Is that… is that your ECR report? That looks like your ECR.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay. Go to the docker file once, docker.lambda, 68505, it's mine, yeah.
Krish NAik: Go to the Docker Lambda file. See, line number 78, this I told you, this has to be…
Krish NAik: Your one. Check your ECR URI and asthma-based debt.
Krish NAik: This is my… so go to the ECR interface in the AWS console, you will be getting… this is your account ID, actually, so you can open that ECR tab.
Krish NAik: See, this is your 28300.
Krish NAik: So you can copy that entire stuff and peel it.
Krish NAik: Anjal, be sure, on the tag part, keep it. Don't remove 3.12 from the end in docker.lambda.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes.
Krish NAik: It's in Notion also, Abhishek, but it's correct.
Krish NAik: Team.3.12 at the NTS. You can comment that line.
Krish NAik: and add from.
Krish NAik: Before that.
Krish NAik: This is not year 6283, your worst 2-8, check that once.
Krish NAik: Okay, it was 6283, I think. I'm not sure, like, I saw 283 a lot, that's why. Just do a confirmation. See, there is 283.
Krish NAik: We have added 6 in front of that.
Krish NAik: Yeah, or use the clipboard option, that is better, the clipboard option was also there.
Krish NAik: Okay, do the testing and then let me know, because this will, again, take time.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so tomorrow's discussion, again in the same, I think, advanced RAG tutorial, there are a few notebooks that were not discussed, we'll be discussing that. CRAG, SRAG, okay, the… those two things.
saurabh verma: Sir, I have sent you the email, this is Saurava, and tomorrow I'll give the demo. There's some error happened.
Krish NAik: Demo for the error, like, to debug.
saurabh verma: No, no, demo I will give of the application I've developed.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay, well tight.
saurabh verma: I was just trying to make it up, and there was some error. Sorry for that.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, fine.
saurabh verma: Are you sure there.
Krish NAik: Let me know.
saurabh verma: And I've sent you the mail for contacting Chris, sir. I've just now sent it.
Krish NAik: Not at all, it's fine. People who are there in Delhi, you can let me know, like.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I'm in Delhi, I'm in Noida. We are in.
Krish NAik: But you're okay, that's fine. Then I will ask Grace separately. Yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright guys, so I think then today we are done. Okay, so you guys do the testing, do it by yourself. See everything I have done in front of you, what is the error, what are the things that worked, everything in front of you. So please do it by yourself, because now in Project 3, at least.
Krish NAik: From the, deployment prospect, I will keep things simple. Again, in project 4, I'm planning ECS with Farget.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally in one of the projects with EKs, because those two are the core ones.
Krish NAik: Because, right now, everything is cheap, but after that, yes, things will be much costlier. But again, like, if you are doing a lot of it.
Krish NAik: For learning purposes, it's fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I'm concluding the session for today. Okay, half now, you can stop sharing your screen, you can test it, and tomorrow. Everybody, please provide me the update. Spend some time in today, because I know people who are joining new in this week. Last week, people have already spent, so it was faster for them.
milind kulkarni: Okay, so please spend some time, take 2 to 3 hours.
Krish NAik: Even for me, also, it took more than 6 to 8 hours.
Krish NAik: All right, everyone, bye-bye. Thanks for joining, let's meet tomorrow.
saurabh verma: Thank you. Bye.